<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Wallography; or The Britton describ'd: Being a pleasant relation of a journey into Wales, wherein are set down several remarkable passages that occur'd in the way thither. And also many choice observables, and notable commemorations, concerning the state and condition, the nature and humor, actions, manners, customs, &amp;c. of that countrey and people. / By W.R. a mighty lover of Welch travels.</title>
            <author>W. R. (William Richards), 1643-1705.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1682</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 129 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 77 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2012-10">2012-10 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B04996</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing R1375D</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R182703</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">52612220</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 52612220</idno>
            <idno type="VID">179526</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B04996)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 179526)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English Books, 1641-1700 ; 2792:10)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Wallography; or The Britton describ'd: Being a pleasant relation of a journey into Wales, wherein are set down several remarkable passages that occur'd in the way thither. And also many choice observables, and notable commemorations, concerning the state and condition, the nature and humor, actions, manners, customs, &amp;c. of that countrey and people. / By W.R. a mighty lover of Welch travels.</title>
                  <author>W. R. (William Richards), 1643-1705.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[14], 127 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for Edward Caudell, bookseller in Bath,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1682.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Imperfect: stained, tightly bound, print show-through with slight loss of text.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the National Library of Scotland.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Voyages and travels --  Wales --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Wales --  Description and travel --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2011-05</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-05</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-11</date>
            <label>Jayne Henley</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-11</date>
            <label>Jayne Henley</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-05</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:179526:1"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:179526:1"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:179526:2" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:179526:2"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:179526:3"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:179526:3"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:179526:4"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:179526:4" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>
               <hi>WALLOGRAPHY;</hi> OR The Britton Deſcrib'd: BEING <hi>A</hi> Pleaſant Relation of a Journey into <hi>Wales,</hi> wherein are ſet down ſeveral Remarkable Paſſages that occur'd in the way thither.</p>
            <p>AND ALSO Many choice Obſervables, and no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>table Commemorations, concer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning the State and Condition, the Nature and Humor, Actions, Manners, Cuſtoms, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> of that Countrey and People.</p>
            <p>By <hi>W. R.</hi> a mighty Lover of <hi>Welch Travels.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON,</hi> Printed for <hi>Edward Caudell</hi> Book<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeller in <hi>Bath.</hi> 1682.</p>
            <pb facs="tcp:179526:5"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:179526:5"/>
            <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
               <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
            </gap>
         </div>
         <div type="dedication">
            <pb facs="tcp:179526:6"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:179526:6"/>
            <head>TO Sir <hi>Richard Wenman</hi> OF CASSWELL In the County of <hi>Oxford</hi> Baronet.</head>
            <opener>
               <salute>SIR!</salute>
            </opener>
            <p>HAving had the Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nour to be employ'd in a <hi>Negotiation</hi> be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tween an <hi>Engliſh</hi> Gentleman and the Ancient <hi>Brittons,</hi> I was not only upon the Borders, and (as it were) the <hi>Limbs</hi>
               <pb facs="tcp:179526:7"/>of <hi>Wales,</hi> but have travell'd through the very <hi>Bowels</hi> of the Country; in which Journey there did ſalute me ſo many <hi>occurrences</hi> worthy of obſer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vation, that I could not for be<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> a Deſcription of them and from preſenting you with the (as I may ſay). <hi>Wallo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>graphy</hi> of my Voyage.</p>
            <p>I make bold to imitate one <hi>Alexander</hi> of <hi>Greece,</hi> who ſti<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> as he went <hi>dragooning</hi> abo<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> the World, deſcrib'd the wa<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>drings, and (as it were) the<note n="*" place="margin">
                  <hi>Tom Coriat.</hi> was a <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> Tra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vellor, who in King<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> 
                  <hi>James</hi> his time beat upon the hoof abo<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap> two or three thouſand miles, and return'd ho<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap> as very a Cox-combe as he went out. <hi>See <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> Travels call'd his Crudities.</hi>
               </note> 
               <hi>Tom Coriatiſm</hi> of his Expeditions; only
<pb facs="tcp:179526:7"/>in this I ſhall differ from him, whereas he gave only a bare <hi>Image</hi> and <hi>Portraicture</hi> of the Country, I ſhall draw the <hi>Cha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>racter</hi> of the <hi>Inhabitants,</hi> and ſhall not only expreſs in a Map or Table the meer <hi>Picture</hi> of the Place, and tell you that here ſtands <hi>one</hi> Town and <hi>twenty</hi> Miles off ſtands ano<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther, but my Deſign is to give you a Narrative of what I ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſerv'd concerning the Nature of the <hi>(1)</hi> Soil, and of the <hi>(2)</hi> Inhabitants, their Origi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nal, Perſons, Diet, Apparel, Language, Laws, Cuſtoms, Policy, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
            </p>
            <pb facs="tcp:179526:8"/>
            <p>But what need I go ſo fa<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> as <hi>Macedonia</hi> for a <hi>Pattern</hi> ſeeing we have ſo many <hi>Pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cedents</hi> at home? For one tell us in <hi>Octavo</hi> that he hath been at <hi>Conſtantinople;</hi> ano<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther that he hath been at <hi>Vi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>enna;</hi> a third that he hath been in <hi>Spain;</hi> and why may not I tell the World in a little Book that I have been in <hi>Wales?</hi> When a Fellow hath either a <hi>Maggot</hi> in his Pate or a <hi>Breeze</hi> in his Tail, that he cannot fix long in a place; or perhaps when he hath <hi>enti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tled</hi> himſelf by ſome miſde<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>meanours either to the Pillory or Gibbet, to <hi>diſinherit</hi> himſelf
<pb facs="tcp:179526:8"/>of his deſerved Right, he <hi>flirts</hi> into <hi>Holland,</hi> or is tranſport<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed into ſome Forreign Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trey; where converſing a lit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tle while, he thruſts into th' World the Hiſtory of his Ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ventures, he <hi>varniſheth</hi> over his Baniſhment with the Name of Travel, and ſtiles that his <hi>Recreation</hi> which was indeed his <hi>Puniſhment,</hi> and ſo <hi>dig<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nifies</hi> a Ramble by the name of Journey. He tells what <hi>Wonderments</hi> have ſurpriz'd him, what <hi>Fragments</hi> of An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tiquity have amaz'd him, what Structures have raviſh'd him, what hills have tir'd him; in a word, he is <hi>big</hi> with Deſcri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ptions,
<pb facs="tcp:179526:9"/>and obliges you with the Narrative of all his Obſer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vations and Notices; ſeeing every one almoſt that hath bu<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>untruſs'd</hi> in a Forreign Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>try, will have his Voyage re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>corded, and every <hi>Letter-Car<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rier</hi> beyond Sea would be thought a <hi>Drake</hi> or a <hi>Candiſh</hi> I thought with my ſelf wh<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> may not I have the liberty o<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> relating my Journey, and o<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> communicating my Obſervati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons to Mankind. I muſt con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feſs my <hi>Pilgrimage</hi> was no<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> far, but perhaps it was <hi>che<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quer'd</hi> with as great variety both of Pleaſure and Peril a<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> a longer Progreſs; neither are
<pb facs="tcp:179526:9"/>my Remarques very ſolemn and ſtately, but yet they were ſuch as gratify'd my curioſity, and pleas'd my humor as well as the Obſervations of longer Jour<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nals.</p>
            <p>Such as they are. (Sir!) I humbly crave leave to devote them to your Peruſal, as the moſt ſignal <hi>Teſtimony<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
               </hi> of that venerable <hi>Eſteem</hi> I have for you. I wave your <hi>Panegy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rick,</hi> and forbear to Rhetori<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cate or to <hi>deſcant</hi> in your Praiſe. You are too <hi>Copious</hi> a Subject even for the moſt <hi>Tranſcendent</hi> Oratory. I liſt not to diſplay your Perſonal Accompliſhments, which are
<pb facs="tcp:179526:10"/>ſo eminent and conſpicuous al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ready in the World. I kno<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> an Attempt of that Nature would be too great a <hi>Violence</hi> to your <hi>Modeſty,</hi> and I am ſure too hard a <hi>Task</hi> for my <hi>Capacity.</hi> My preſent Buſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs (Sir!) is to put this lit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tle Book into your Hand, and to deſire you to <hi>Honour</hi> the Author in accepting, and to <hi>Divert</hi> your ſelf in reading of it; for poſſibly you may find ſo much <hi>Comody</hi> in this <hi>Walk,</hi> as may diſpoſe you to ſmile away an hour in the per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uſal of it. The Relations are not <hi>common</hi> and <hi>ordinary,</hi> and perhaps as pleaſant as they
<pb facs="tcp:179526:10"/>are <hi>rare</hi> and <hi>unuſual.</hi> I do not know that any Travellor <hi>jogging</hi> in the <hi>ſame</hi> Road hath given the <hi>ſame</hi> Account of Things, or hath made the ſame Deſcriptions which I here preſent you with; ſo that my Remarques are <hi>ſpick and ſpan</hi> new, and if they are <hi>ridicu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lous,</hi> they are not unlike the Perſons upon whom they are written. For the <hi>Welch</hi> Peo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple are a pretty <hi>odd ſort</hi> of Mortals, and I hope I have given you a pretty <hi>odd Cha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>racter</hi> of them, and ſo I think I am pretty <hi>even</hi> with them for <hi>Oddneſs.</hi> A Taphy is ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſerv'd to be a <hi>Trickiſh</hi> Ani<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mal,
<pb facs="tcp:179526:11"/>that hath a Vein of <hi>Jac<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>puddiniſ<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> running throu<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> all his Actions, and therefore I thought it not improper ſprinble here and there ſome what of the <hi>Blew-jacket,</hi> a<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> to <hi>Merry-Andrew</hi> my Pr<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>graſs a little farther as I we with jocund Obſervations, th<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> the <hi>Hiſtory</hi> might be agreeab<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> to the <hi>Matter</hi> it Treats So that if a <hi>Welch-man</hi> is <hi>Jeſt,</hi> as all the World <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> count him a Living <hi>Pun,</hi> 
               <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> walking <hi>Conundrum,</hi> and breathing <hi>Witticiſm;</hi> Th<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> have I made one Joke up another.</p>
            <pb facs="tcp:179526:11"/>
            <p>I am not unſenſible that Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ers of another Nature and Complexion are more agreeable <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> that <hi>Character</hi> you bear in <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>he World; <hi>Machiavel</hi> and <hi>Malvezzi,</hi> or ſome diſcourſe of be Maxims of <hi>Policy,</hi> would <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>e a more ſutable Subject for <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ur Contemplation: But (Sir!) <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> pretend not to inſtruct you for <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>he <hi>Parliament-houſe,</hi> but to <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>irect you by the <hi>Fire-ſide.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Now for the Concluſion of <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ll; If there are any <hi>Good Things</hi> in <hi>Wales,</hi> the enjoy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment whereof is worth the wiſh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing you, I pray Heaven to <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>rown you with the Fruition of <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>hem: But poſſibly it may be
<pb facs="tcp:179526:12" rendition="simple:additions"/>a Province not much <hi>crowde</hi> with Bleſſings; may you the<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore Flouriſh in the Affluen of good <hi>Engliſh</hi> Mercies; m<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> you always poſſeſs good <hi>Engli<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> Riches, Health and Honour and all other Happineſſes an<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> Proſperities of our own N<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion!</p>
            <closer>I am,
<salute>(Worthy Sir!)</salute>
               <signed>Your very Humble Servant <hi>W. R.</hi>
               </signed>
               <dateline>Helmdon, <date>Octob. <hi>24. 1681.</hi>
                  </date>
               </dateline>
            </closer>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:179526:12" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <head>WALLOGRAPHY OR The Britton deſcrib'd, &amp;c.</head>
            <p>UPon the Firſt of <hi>June</hi> 1673, having taken leave of my Friends, and recei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ved a Meſſage, a little tiny Er<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rend to be uttered by word of mouth, together with a Letter to <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>e deliver'd into the hands of one of the moſt Reverend Taphies, <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> began to have ſome thoughts <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>f <hi>rigging</hi> my ſelf out for mine <gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>tended Voyage; and to that and I ſpatterdaſh't my Legs with <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> pair of Cuckolds boots, and ei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther adorn'd or furniſh't my hand
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:179526:13"/>with battooning Cudgel, and ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving entertain'd in my Retinue whole <hi>Diſtick</hi> of Spannels.</p>
            <p>Upon the Fourth of <hi>June,</hi> turn'd one ſide upon <hi>London,</hi> an<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> the other toward <hi>Wales;</hi> the Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>try which was to be the Perio<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> and Term of my Journey. W<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> travelled all that day with much pleaſure, being treated as w<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> went, with the <hi>Delicacies</hi> of Na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ture: the Air was <hi>kind</hi> and <hi>ſof<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> the Fields were <hi>trim</hi> and <hi>neat;</hi> 
               <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> Sun <hi>benign</hi> and <hi>cheriſhing;</hi> 
               <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> whole Creation was <hi>obliging,</hi> and from every thing we met, w<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> receiv'd a <hi>Civility;</hi> ſo that th<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> firſt day paſs'd over with mu<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> ſatisfaction. I do not remembe<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> that we ſaw any thing remarkable unleſs 'twas a Fellow driving <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>tyr'd Cow,</hi> whoſe ſlow motion <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> now and then quickn'd by wri<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing the <hi>Pendulum</hi> of her Tail a<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> (as it were) curling it into a ſcre<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <pb n="3" facs="tcp:179526:13"/>he <hi>twiſted</hi> her forward, and bor'd the Air with this Living <hi>Augre;</hi> Me-thoughts a very pretty trick to make a wimble of his Beaſt, and a handſome way to inſinuate her along, and to improve her pace. 'Twas far beyond the court<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhip of a wiſp of hay, in regard <hi>Fear</hi> urges more than <hi>Flattery</hi> can allure, and all Creatures are more ready to eaſe their <hi>Backs,</hi> than to fill their <hi>Bellies;</hi> O how Scorpions pretty crabbedly apply'd will make a thing caper, and increaſe his Career far beyond the <hi>temptation</hi> of Cake and Marmalade! and a Cat of <hi>Nine-Tails</hi> will drive bet<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter than a diſh of Sweet meats can invite and draw. This was the Method the Bumpkin us'd to ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vance the <hi>progreſſive Motion</hi> of the Animal; which indeed is far different from the Cuſtom and Practice of the <hi>Croatians;</hi> For whereas this man made his Beaſt
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:179526:14"/>proceed by thruſting at <hi>one en<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> the Tail; They make their ty<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> Jades jog on by putting at th<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> other, the <hi>Fore-top.</hi> We bega<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> to ſubſcribe to <hi>Carteſius</hi>'s opinio<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> that Animals were Engins; F<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> 'tis like, the <hi>Clock-work</hi> of th<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> Cow was ſomewhat diſorder'<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> and the Machine (like a Jack<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> was run down and ſtood ſtill, <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> this Artiſt wound it up, and <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> the movements a going.</p>
            <p>Being indifferently refreſht <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> the vertue of that Paſſage, <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> went forward very couragiou<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> and after a little time were p<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſented with the proſpect of an<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Scene, which was laid in Meddow by a River-ſide, wh<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> we overtook a <hi>Rat-catcher</hi> and <hi>Fiſherman</hi> diſputing Preceden<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> and the Preheminency of th<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> Profeſſions: The Rat-catcher <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> gu'd that his Calling was moſt w<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thy, in regard the object of <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap>
               <pb n="5" facs="tcp:179526:14"/>Art was a <hi>vocal Creature,</hi> whereas that of the Fiſherman's was <hi>dumb</hi> and <hi>ſilent;</hi> beſides Rats are edu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cated in Courts and Palaces, are more choicely bred, and have a more delicate diet, than Fiſh, to ſeed on; Plentiful Reverſions of Roſt and Boyl'd, luxurious frag<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments, and the <hi>magnificent ruines</hi> of Pudding and Paſty are their common diſhes; only ſometimes they pop on a piece of <hi>Bread</hi> and <hi>Butter</hi> not of ſo wholſome a re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liſh, that is, a little <hi>Arſenick</hi> ſpread for 'um on the <hi>trencher</hi> of a Chip, theſe are the <hi>Viands</hi> of this do<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>meſtick <hi>Vermin;</hi> whereas Worms and Flies, and vile Inſects, and perhaps a hook to boot, are the beſt <hi>Fare</hi> that is eaten by Fiſhes. The <hi>Fiſherman</hi> reply'd, that Fiſh themſelves were food for men, but it was never known that Rats were in ſeaſon, unleſs in the <hi>extremity</hi> of a Siege or Famine.</p>
            <pb n="6" facs="tcp:179526:15"/>
            <p>We left theſe Fellows very <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> in controverſy, which could <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> be decided, and paſs'd on, till <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> length we arrived to a little kno<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> or <hi>Aſteriſm</hi> of houſes ſtanding, <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> rather lying on the <hi>Crump</hi> of a Hi<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rais'd ſomewhat <hi>proudly</hi> above <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> ordinary level; and methough<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> look<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> down with ſomewhat <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>Diſdain</hi> upon the Humble V<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lies. Who was the Founder <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> this <hi>Hamlet</hi> is not certainly know<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> but we perceiv'd the <hi>Thacker</hi> h<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> been a great <hi>Benefactor.</hi> As <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> the Nativity of the Place, <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> Foundation was laid under an <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> fortunate <hi>Configuration</hi> of the H<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vens: ſo that the <hi>Tinkers</hi> and <hi>Ca<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lers,</hi> and the dregs of manki<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> that dwelt there; expected <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> Proſperity, nor hop'd to be <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> vanc'd and ſublimated into <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>Flower</hi> of the People. The ma<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>ſtreſs</hi> of Government lay upon <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>ſhoulder</hi> of a ſingle man, who wa<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <pb n="7" facs="tcp:179526:15"/>
               <hi>
                  <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ear-ward</hi> by Office, and being <gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>e moſt ſubſtantial Perſon was <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>hought fit to be <hi>inveſted</hi> with <gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>e ſole Authority of the Town<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap>p; A moſt proper Magiſtrate <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> ſuch wild Savages! We ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>rv'd that this Village had as ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>y ways <hi>into</hi> it, as it had ways <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> of it, which were equal in <gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>mber to the Points of the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>ſs. The <hi>purling</hi> Brook that <gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>wl'd by it, the <hi>reeking</hi> Dung<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>ll that breath'd within it, the <hi>
                  <gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>ook-back'd</hi> Elm that ſtands <hi>cring<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>g</hi> near it, and the Pack-<hi>ſaddle</hi> 
               <gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>eeple that ſtood <hi>ſquinting</hi> over <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> made a pretty Draught of an and ſome <hi>Landskip.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>The Inhabitants of this place <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ere much addicted to the vice of <hi>
                  <gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>ealing;</hi> every thing <hi>ſticks</hi> to <gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>eir Pitchy Fingers, and they <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ave ſuch an <hi>attractive</hi> vertue, that, <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>herever they come, all things <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ot after the Magnetiſm of their
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:179526:16"/>Perſons. A Fellow ſquotting <gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on a criket in a room we w<gap reason="illegible" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap> in, and riſing up from his ſe<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> the ſtool on a ſudden (as if ta<gap reason="illegible" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap> to his A—) immediately mar<gap reason="illegible" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap> after him, to the great amazem<gap reason="illegible" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap> of the woman of the houſe, w<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> did not ſuſpect that his <hi>Bum</hi> 
               <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>hands,</hi> or that her <hi>Stool</hi> ſo n<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bly could have us'd its <hi>legs.</hi> A<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther eſpying a <hi>Cylinder</hi> of B<gap reason="illegible" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap> pudding pretty thick in the <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> lolling upon the table, whilſt <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> Hoſteſs turn'd her back, in <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> very <hi>twinkling</hi> of her head, <hi>pocu<gap reason="illegible" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> it into Fob, and ſo ſhrow<gap reason="illegible" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap> its Dimenſions into a ſec<gap reason="illegible" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap> Bag.</p>
            <p>The <hi>approaching</hi> night and <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> wearied <hi>limbs</hi> compell'd us <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> lodge among theſe Teneme<gap reason="illegible" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap> Having almoſt <hi>worn</hi> out our ſe<gap reason="illegible" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap> by tedious Travel, we reſol<gap reason="illegible" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap> here to repair our <hi>breeches:</hi> 
               <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> (alas!) this <hi>mending</hi> (I allud<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <pb n="9" facs="tcp:179526:16"/>
               <hi>Taylouriſm</hi>) was little better than meer <hi>Botching.</hi> For, whereas we thought to have renew'd nature, and to have recreated our Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lates with the pleaſant whole<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſomeneſs of <hi>Rural Delicacies,</hi> we could ſcarce ſo much as even patch her up with the <hi>hurden Accomo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dations</hi> of a red-lattic'd Inn; The <hi>foretop</hi> of a Carrot, and a few parcht Peaſe were our choiceſt Provender, which fill'd our ca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vities ſo full of wind, that we thought we had got the <hi>Four Quarters</hi> in our Bellys, which made ſuch <hi>Squibs</hi> of our Breeches, that (like the fifth of <hi>November</hi>) we were continually diſcharging of <hi>Rockets</hi> and <hi>Crackers.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>The next day dreſs'd with <hi>Au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rora,</hi> nay before ſhe had put on her <hi>Indian</hi> gown, we ſet out with the Sun, who bearing us company but a little while withdrew into an apartment behind a cloud, at
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:179526:17"/>whoſe abſence the Heavens <hi>frown<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing</hi> and contracting their brows, did preſently fall a crying and wept ſuch plentiful ſhowers of tears, that they moiſtn'd our skin<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> with the <hi>Deluge</hi> of their Grief. But that which terrify'd us moſt of all, was <hi>water</hi> which we ſaw of ſeve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ral colours, ſometimes <hi>red,</hi> and ſometimes <hi>black;</hi> which put us in mind of thoſe <hi>Prodigious Rains</hi> the Philoſophers ſpeak of, <hi>Blood</hi> and <hi>Ink;</hi> But overtaking a <hi>Col<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lier</hi> and <hi>Red-Oker</hi> man, we per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceiv'd 'twas the <hi>Diſtillations</hi> of their Buggets. But that which gave <hi>wings</hi> to time, and made it <hi>fly</hi> merrily while we were in the company of theſe Vagrants, were the frequent <hi>Quarrels</hi> that were <hi>broacht</hi> between them, which at length were improv'd into ſevere <hi>Buffetings.</hi> The <hi>Object</hi> of both their Occupations lyes hid in the Earth, and they work like Moles,
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:179526:17"/>whoſe Employ is <hi>underground,</hi> and (like a certain Fiſh) they take their <hi>colour</hi> from the place they converſe in. The Collier thumpt with <hi>tincturing</hi>-fiſt the Red-man, black; and the Red man dy'd with <hi>Vermilion</hi>- blow the Black<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man, red; ſo that we never ſaw before ſuch a <hi>party colour'd</hi> Cour<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bat, ſuch a <hi>Fool's-coa<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ed</hi> conflict<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>, wherein thelſt out Champions were ſo mutually diſguis'd, that they ſeem'd to be <hi>Amphituo'd,</hi> and to be wholly transform'd into each others Perſon.</p>
            <p>After another days Travel in Duſt and Sun, we ſaluted a good handſome Town, not a little re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſembling in crookedneſs a middle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſiz'd <hi>ſhooing horn;</hi> At the entrance into it, the <hi>uncarpetneſs</hi> (as I may ſay) of the Floor, or (in other words) the <hi>unevenneſs</hi> of the ſtreets ſomewhat diſlocating the poſition of our almoſt <hi>tript up</hi>
               <pb n="12" facs="tcp:179526:18"/>feet, had like to have demoliſh us, and to have thrown us dow<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> backward, but to prevent the <hi>S<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lœciſm</hi> of kiſſing the place at <hi>wron<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> end,</hi> we recovered our fall, an<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> went bolt upright into the <hi>nave<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> of the Coporation, where the<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> was ſuch an <hi>Aſſembly</hi> of Proviſio<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> as repreſented a market, whic<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> was unhappily diſturb'd by an u<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fortunate accident; For a <hi>certai<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> Bull</hi> of an <hi>uncertain</hi> man havin<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> miſtaken his <hi>box,</hi> and taken <hi>peppe<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> in the noſe inſtead of <hi>Snuſh,</hi> a<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> being enrag'd and heated by th<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> vertue of the Spice, took a ris<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> about the Croſs, and emptied b<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> his Ramble all Stalls and Panniers ſo that this <hi>Brisk Cuſtomer</hi> made <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> ſcrambling kind of Dinner for th<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> whole Country; who was ridi<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> upon one anothers backs for V<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ands and Booty, and was tu<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bling among the <hi>ruins</hi> of Bake<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> Victuallers, and Coſtermonge<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <pb n="13" facs="tcp:179526:18"/>We were inform'd that this Town was much infeſted with the un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>welcome Viſitants, <hi>Rats</hi> and <hi>Mice;</hi> inſomuch that the Inhabitants have a <hi>Rat-catcher</hi> at a certain Penſion, as the only <hi>Talis-man</hi> againſt ſuch noxious Vermin.</p>
            <p>Having left this <hi>Town</hi> behind us, we come to a <hi>Wood</hi> on our left hand, nigh unto which was a diſcontented Fountain <hi>murmuring</hi> as it run (we did not enquire a what) and <hi>bubling</hi> forth ſeemingly much Diſſatisfaction. This wood was a <hi>promiſcuous Rabble</hi> of all vege<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ables. A <hi>throng</hi> of trees of all ranks and qualities; we refreſht ourſelves a little under this natural <hi>Arbour,</hi> and being prety and cheerful in this circumſtance of Place; one of our <hi>Caravan</hi> began to expreſs his joy in ſome notes of Muſick, who as ſoon as he began to ſtrike up with his <hi>Pite</hi> (thinking he had but one) he preſently preceiv'd it to be
<pb n="14" facs="tcp:179526:19"/>multiply'd into an <hi>Organ,</hi> and wonder'd (with the Bumpkin that pull'd at the Bellows) that he had ſo much Harmony in him<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> For you muſt know hereabout<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> dwelt a thing called an <hi>Eceho,</hi> who as ſoon as ſhe heard but <hi>Sol, Fa<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> whipt! ſhe improv'd the melody into a <hi>noiſe</hi> and <hi>conſort:</hi> and pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſently increas'd thoſe ſingle note into the whole <hi>Gamut;</hi> and moſ<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> neately play'd the <hi>wag</hi> with th<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>tail</hi> of his voice! being a ver<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> pretty <hi>Songſter,</hi> that ſings well b<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> th' Ear. But while <hi>Lug</hi> was ſo lac'd with the tatling <hi>Reverbera<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion</hi> of voice, our <hi>eyes</hi> were ra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viſht with a moſt delicate <hi>Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpect;</hi> For here was a moſt plea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſant champion piece of ground which extending and roaming <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> ſelf ſome Furlongs in length, w<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> furniſht with all the <hi>Excellen<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> that ever commended the mo<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>tranſporting Eliſium;</hi> the Air w<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>
               <pb n="15" facs="tcp:179526:19"/>
               <hi>lullaby'd</hi> as ſtill and quiet as Dor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mant Infant; the Day was Ori<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ent, bright and clear; the Earth (like a Foreſter) was clad in green. The Figure of this Field was a <hi>Parallellogrammum,</hi> the Style was ſituate South-Eaſt-by North, and conſiſted of a <hi>climax</hi> of three rails, over which we convey'd our ſelves by <hi>Elevation of Leg;</hi> near the entrance into the Mea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dow, we obſerv'd an hole or <hi>caſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment</hi> in the hedge, which we per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceiv'd the Hogs had oftentimes <hi>threded;</hi> but the Hedger had <hi>glaz'd</hi> it with a <hi>pane</hi> of Furze.</p>
            <p>Having ambled over ſome Fur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>longs on this (as it were) <hi>New-Market</hi> Heath, we perceiv'd it to degenerate and to grow worſe and worſe, and (like an handſome neck of Mutton) to determine in the unevenneſs of a Rock, or Scrag. A little while after we winded a <hi>Cordwainer,</hi> who (as he
<pb n="16" facs="tcp:179526:20"/>told us) was newly recover'd from a ſad <hi>miſchance;</hi> For walking care<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>leſsly, one day he happen'd to have a fall, and to <hi>ſquot</hi> his Breech upon an <hi>Hedg-hog,</hi> which he carry'd away as cleverly, (it clinging to his Buttocks) as if he had ſate up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on a <hi>ball</hi> of his wax; whether there is a ſimpathy between a <hi>Shooma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>kers</hi> tail, and the skin of an <hi>
                  <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>r<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chin,</hi> or whether the <hi>briſtles</hi> of the Creature entred the <hi>pores</hi> of his Backſide, we liſt not to decide that controverſie now; but how<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ever the mortal complain'd that it was an uneaſy <hi>cuſhion,</hi> and that that <hi>Spinny</hi> of Awls had made a <hi>cullender</hi> of his A—: But being not much concern'd at the <hi>cerebro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſity</hi> of his <hi>ſeivy</hi> Bum; The <hi>Ilet<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>holes</hi> whereof being not very deep, we went together, till we arriv'd to the <hi>roughneſs</hi> of the foremen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tioned Downs, which did ſome<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>what decline into an uneven <hi>Prae<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cipice,</hi>
               <pb n="17" facs="tcp:179526:20"/>whoſe craggy ſtairs as ſoon as we had deſcended, we ſtumbled upon an Houſe, or a Dung<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hill modell'd into the ſhape of a Cottage, whoſe outward ſurface was ſo all to-be-negro'd with ſuch ſwarthy plaiſter, that it ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pear'd not unlike a great blot of Cow-turd: This Structure ſtradled <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ver about eight Ells of ground, <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>bove the ſurface whereof the <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ves were advanc'd about two <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ards, and the Chimney peep'd <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ut about a Foot above the Eves; <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>he light flow'd in through the <hi>old <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ircumference</hi> of a bottomleſs <hi>Peck;</hi> which being ſtuck in the Thatch, <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>upply'd the place of an <hi>Orbicular</hi> Caſement. The Door-way was a <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>reach in the wall toward one end, which being of a dwarfiſh ſize, <hi>i. e.</hi> 
               <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>wo Foot lower in ſtature than an ordinary Man, we were forc'd to a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ridge our Dimenſions, and to
<pb n="18" facs="tcp:179526:21"/>creep in. The Parlour, H<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> Kitchin, <hi>i. e.</hi> one Room wich was prettily adorn'd with the <hi>P<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>try</hi> of <hi>Ballads;</hi> a <hi>crippled</hi> Pip<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> with a broken ſhin, near ally'd a Diſh of the ſame matter; a <hi>vo<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> Spoon with a Whiſtle at the en<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> and a <hi>Tipſy</hi> Cradle reeling in t<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> corner, (methoughts) were a <hi>pr<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>ty</hi> ſort of <hi>Goods,</hi> and not <hi>unhan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſome Furniture.</hi> A whole <hi>Lit<gap reason="illegible" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> of Children was <hi>ſtrew'd</hi> upon t<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> Floor; only one <hi>Mopp-headed</hi> B<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> was <hi>Tripos'd</hi> on a Cricket, a<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> blew the Fire; The carv'd Ma<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>tle-tree ſeem'd to be defended <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> a little <hi>wooden</hi> Fellow furiou<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> ſtrutting in an <hi>Oaken</hi> Cloak; a<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> we perceiv'd the Window was <hi>
                  <gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dors'd</hi> with the Picture of a <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> We obſerv'd that the <hi>Bulkie</hi> C<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>board was a Nuſance to the wh<gap reason="illegible" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>Family</hi> of Houſhold-ſtuff, wh<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> it had mightily diſoblig'd by <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap>
               <pb n="19" facs="tcp:179526:21"/>trenching on their Liberties, they grutching it ſo much room; and indeed the Table, Bed, and other Utenſils have not ſuffer'd a little detriment by its injurious <hi>Contigui<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty.</hi> We had a Proſpect of whole <hi>Territories</hi> about this Building, which though not large, yet were exceedingly well fortify'd; a lit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tle Hedge being a <hi>Pallizado</hi> on one ſide, and a narrow Trench in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtead of a <hi>Bulwark</hi> on the other: The <hi>Continuity</hi> of the Mound was <hi>violated</hi> by a <hi>Notch</hi> in the corner to ſet a Stile in; over which when we had paſſed, we eſpy'd a Bank like a little <hi>Hybla,</hi> cap'd with a Hive of Bees, which this ſmall <hi>Eden</hi> curi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ouſly carv'd, and (as it were) <hi>Quincunx'd</hi> into a Knot, did feaſt with the moiſture of its delicious Flowers. Leaving the <hi>Phylacteries</hi> of this Yard, we met the Good-Houſewife of this little Tenement
<pb n="20" facs="tcp:179526:22"/>with her Tippet <hi>briſtling,</hi> 
               <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> Mouth <hi>mumping,</hi> and her Han<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>knitting;</hi> ſhe had a <hi>Cade</hi> Lamb her <hi>Rere,</hi> attending upon her, a<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> a <hi>Kitten</hi> in the <hi>Van,</hi> conducting <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> home.</p>
            <p>We follow'd our Noſes fro<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> hence, and were directed by <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>Clue</hi> of a long Hedge; which af<gap reason="illegible" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap> a great extent in length, we fou<gap reason="illegible" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap> to be <hi>Tagg'd</hi> with a rough La<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> turning from which a little towa<gap reason="illegible" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap> the right, we overtook a <hi>Chur<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> ſtanding (like an Ace) and m<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>ping by it ſelf, at ſome diſtan<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> from the Town; which wheth<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>it</hi> run from the Pariſh, or the P<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſh <hi>from it,</hi> we are not as yet i<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>form'd; though we have moſt re<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon to ſuſpect the <hi>latter;</hi> in rega<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> as to outward appearance t<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> weak Conſtitution of the Fabric ſeem'd not much to be addicted run. It ſeem'd to be very cra<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>
               <pb n="21" facs="tcp:179526:22"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>nd had a <hi>muſſler</hi> of Ivy, which we preſume were inſtead of <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>rutches; For whereas that feeble Vegetable is uſually <hi>upheld</hi> by the walls it clings to, we believe it was a <hi>Buttreſſe</hi> here to ſupport the Walls. But having ſadden'd our Aſpect with the melancholy looks of this deſolate Temple, we took our leave of it, and ſhot directly <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>own a <hi>Balk</hi> upon that prophane Town to which it ſeem'd to ſtand related. At our firſt ſalutation whereof, we chanc'd to pop into a dapper <hi>Ale-houſe,</hi> mightily ſtufft with a huge Hoſteſſe, whoſe moi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſture diſtilling through the Pores of her Body, and being ſomewhat turn'd through exceſſive heat, ſtruck our <hi>olfactive</hi> Nerves with ſo great a ſowrneſs, that we had quite been overcome with this <hi>Veſſel of Vineger,</hi> had ſhe not too much jog'd her ſelf by an unhappy
<pb n="22" facs="tcp:179526:23"/>fall, and ſpilt a great quantity o<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> her unctuous Liquor.</p>
            <p>The Shoomaker conjectur'd tha<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> ſhe had loſt about five or ſix pound <hi>(aver-du-pois)</hi> from her <hi>Rere</hi> be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hind, and preſently concluded tha<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> ſhe was in great danger of hanging all <hi>a-one-ſide,</hi> unleſs ſome charita<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble Perſon ſhould poize her with thruſt of <hi>aſſisting Noſe.</hi> We had ſcarce <hi>prim'd</hi> our Pipes, but in comes a <hi>Law-jobber,</hi> accompanied with the <hi>Bum-bruſher,</hi> or School<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>maſter of the place, who after ſome time, took occaſion to ſhew their skill and breeding at Fifty-cuffs, but (thanks to the Stars) without any <hi>danger</hi> to their Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feſſions; For they did not ſo much aim at the <hi>head,</hi> as level their fury at each others <hi>heels,</hi> where their knowledge was ſuppos'd not to <hi>lye,</hi> though ſome hold that they have as much Learning <hi>at one end</hi>
               <pb n="23" facs="tcp:179526:23"/>as they have at <hi>t'other.</hi> The moſt remarkable thing in this Village was a <hi>Carrot-pate</hi> houſe at the <hi>Po<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſteriours</hi> of the Town; it was co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver'd with Tile, and was curiouſly contriv'd after the <hi>Italian</hi> Models. The Maſter that did animate, or the <gap reason="foreign">
                  <desc>〈 in non-Latin alphabet 〉</desc>
               </gap> of this Stone-carcaſs (they told us) was lately dead: His Diſtemper was a <hi>Quarrel</hi> be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tween his Belly and his Back; the one being <hi>bursten</hi> took pet and run away from the other, ſo that the poor Man being at a loſs for a place to put his Victuals in, <hi>dy'd</hi> with a conceit.</p>
            <p>S. <hi>Criſpin</hi>'s Diſciple having a Miſtreſs in this Lordſhip, and be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing almoſt within the <hi>Atmoſphere</hi> of her preſence, began to <hi>wind</hi> her, and had a great tendency to the place where ſhe was; ſo that I might as ſoon expect that a ſtone ſhould fall beyond the center, as
<pb n="24" facs="tcp:179526:24"/>that this <hi>Gentle-crafts-man</hi> ſhou<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> budge further; wherefore nothi<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> was expected now but an imme<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ate <hi>Divorce</hi> from each others co<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pany; but before we parted, <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> oblig'd me with the Proſpect bo<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> of her Perſon and Fortune. <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> for the firſt, as ſoon as I ſaw it, <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> had greater reaſon to congratula<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> my Eye-ſight than I had before for ſhe was bleſt with a moſt <hi>raviſ<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing</hi> Aſpect, and a ſnug Face, mo<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> prodigiouſly grac'd with a dain<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> fine Noſe, faſten'd in its middle which is not like ſome Snouts tha<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> look more upon one Cheek, tha<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> they do upon the other, but ſhew<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> equal reſpect to both, not at al<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>diſobliging</hi> the right by <hi>fleering</hi> to<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> much on the left. And then fo<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> her Eyes, they are excellent a<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> twireing, and will be ſure to kee<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> her Noſe <hi>ſafe,</hi> (I'le warrant you <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> for one looks <hi>one</hi> way, and the o<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ther
<pb n="25" facs="tcp:179526:24"/>
               <hi>another.</hi> The Woman had a Mouth too, which was ſomewhat bigger than that of a Musket, though not twice as big as the ca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pacious bore of a Blew Noggin. This Mouth ſhe put but to <hi>one uſe,</hi> and that's the ſame that we put ours to, that is to eat three or four Meals in a day; for it ſeems where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>as other Women often uſe theirs in <hi>prating</hi> and <hi>twatling,</hi> we perceiv'd that this <hi>ſav'd</hi> her <hi>Mouth</hi> and ſpake through her <hi>Noſe.</hi> As we have given you the Picture of her Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon, ſo now let's preſent you with a Landskip of her Fortune. As for her Lands, that is, Paſture-ground, and Meadow, we could not diſcern, but that (like a ſpot upon the Globe) they took but little room upon the ſurface of the Earth, and (like the Poſſeſſions of <hi>Alcibiades</hi>) were but a little ſpeck to the World. A little Muck
<pb n="26" facs="tcp:179526:25"/>would dung her Fallow; one hig<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> Table T— (to ſpeak in the <hi>Ox<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ford</hi> Dialect) will much enrich it and an Ear of Corn will go near to ſow it; 'tis like ſhe hath Graſs e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nough for a couple of Rabbets Having ſurvey'd the Paramour and the Portion of this Nivelling Cobler, after a ſingle ſip of fixe<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> out of a Tin Pot, and a <hi>Trebl<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> go-down out of a cup of <hi>Doubl<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> after a <hi>right-line</hi> ſcrape with <hi>lef<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> Leg; and uncouth doffing of <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> bad Bonnet, after <hi>ſlinking</hi> a Com<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>plement by way of thanks for hi<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> Society, attended by his Cobler<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hood to the confines of a Yard, a<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> the claſping together of two lowr<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ing Gates in the preſence of a <hi>Cor<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>pulent</hi> and <hi>Burly</hi> Elme, I ſolemnl<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> took leave of my Fellow-Trave<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ler. After his departure I wa<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> forc'd to beguile away the time <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> the ſhady <hi>ſolitude</hi> of ſilent thought
<pb n="27" facs="tcp:179526:25"/>which before I ſpent in the <hi>brisker Entertainments</hi> of Diſcourſe and Dialogue: I had not long buſy'd my faculties with inward ſpecula<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions, but I met with variety of Objects courting with their <hi>Flatte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ries</hi> my almoſt diſtracted Contem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plations. I ſaw <hi>Three Stones</hi> ſo artificially ſet, that they repreſent<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed the Figure of a convenient <hi>Stile.</hi> Methoughts the Archite<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cture of it was very curious; for one ſtone about a Foot ſquare, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing plac'd perpendiculary upright, its Northern Extremity was croſs'd by another at right Angles; on the other ſide whereof was ere<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cted another perpendicular corre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpondent to the former. The Po<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſition of theſe Materials made a pretty Fabrick, over which a Man might commodiouſly paſs; its ſur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>face was ſmooth, not <hi>tufted</hi> with ſnags, which are always catching
<pb n="28" facs="tcp:179526:26"/>and <hi>ſnarling</hi> at your Cloaths, <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> the great <hi>Diſguize</hi> and Damage <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> your Breeches; about two yard<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> diſtant there was a Croſs delv'd i<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> the Earth, which ſeem'd either a<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> Argument of <hi>Popiſh Superstition</hi> or a Sign or Mark of the Pariſ<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>Selvidge.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Departing from hence, w<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> mov'd through a Cloſe very <hi>pop<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>lous</hi> with Mutton; there being (as it were) a whole <hi>Academy</hi> 
               <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> Sheep <hi>ſizeing</hi> on a Hay-rick, no<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> botled out into Commons, bu<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> Geometrically carv'd into goo<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>Sexangular</hi> Luncheons. 'Twa<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> Foot-cloath'd (as it were) wit<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> Straw near five yards about, upo<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> which were tumbling a <hi>Bag-piper<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> and an <hi>Hocus,</hi> who wanton'd ſ<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> long till (like Dogs) at laſt thei<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> Play determin'd in a ſharp conflic<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> The Man of Muſick buffeted th<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> Jugler to <hi>ſome tune,</hi> who addin<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <pb n="29" facs="tcp:179526:26"/>two or three <hi>howls</hi> to the <hi>Notes</hi> of his Drone-pipe, by cleanly con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veyance did vaniſh from him. The Piper appear'd of a tawny Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plexion, his <hi>Noſe</hi> bending with an Arch upward; his <hi>Eyes</hi> being ſomewhat hollow, ſeem'd to in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>creaſe the <hi>promontory</hi> of his jetting Forehead. In a word, there was <hi>charm</hi> enough in his Aſpect; He was well built, his whole <hi>Frame</hi> and contexture was <hi>ſweet</hi> and <hi>regu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lar;</hi> I muſt needs ſay, I have ſel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom met with any handſomer <hi>Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>del,</hi> or <hi>Platform</hi> of a Man. But though his <hi>Perſon</hi> was neat and <hi>uniform,</hi> yet his habit and <hi>garb</hi> was full of <hi>deformity,</hi> and there were as many <hi>Soloeciſms</hi> and <hi>Incohoeren<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cies</hi> on theſe, as there was <hi>Congrui<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ies</hi> and <hi>Beauty</hi> commendable in that. He wore a <hi>Miſ<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ellany</hi> of Apparel, a <hi>Gallimafry</hi> of Cloaths, as I humbly conceive, 'twas a <hi>Tyth
<pb n="30" facs="tcp:179526:27"/>Suit,</hi> compos'd of various and ſ<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>veral ſorts; ſuch a <hi>Club</hi> of Ragg<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> and <hi>Randeſvouz</hi> of Fragments muſt needs be a Collection (lik<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> the Jerkin of the Jay) of ſever<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> Feathers from divers Birds. H<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> Doublet (which indeed was b<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> one great Patch in <hi>Folio</hi>) was v<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ry <hi>heterogeneous</hi> from the reſt <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> his Attire; he had worn his La<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>pets into perfect <hi>Fringe,</hi> (ſo th<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> he ſeem'd to be ſurrounded wi<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> the <hi>remnant</hi> of a Curtain) a<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> had <hi>thin'd</hi> his Elbows into the firſt <hi>Principles.</hi> 'Twas of a Mou<gap reason="illegible" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap> colour hue, and (as near as could gueſs) it appear'd to be t<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>Reſult</hi> of an old Cloak; both <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> firſt <hi>Crop</hi> and <hi>Latter-Math</hi> too we<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> both worn off; and it was <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> Thread-bare, that it had alm<gap reason="illegible" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>founder'd</hi> three or four of his <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> Lice; wherefore we advis'd <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> to hang it no longer on a <hi>Kna<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi>
               <pb n="31" facs="tcp:179526:27"/>back, but to condemn it to the Houſewifery of a Shooe-clout. The Relicks that were left of his tatter'd Breeches were one <hi>Story</hi> pendulous below his Coat. His Inſtrument (like a Gizzard) was tuck'd under his arm, which by <hi>ſhog</hi> of Elbow, he did <hi>hug</hi> into harmony, and <hi>ſqueeze</hi> out of its Womb moſt raviſhing Ditties. We made but few Remarks on the Perſon of the Jugler, only we thought it appear'd to be ſome<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>what <hi>ſleathy;</hi> his Noddle was ſhrowded under the <hi>Patronage</hi> of a collop'd Hat, whoſe <hi>indented</hi> Margin being ſomewhat frail, de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>clin'd from the equality of an <hi>Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rizontal</hi> Poſition, and flapping in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ward on both ſides, and hugging his Ears, forc'd the poor Man to look as it were through a <hi>Spout.</hi> He had a bunch of Ribbond in his hand, which poſſibly might be
<pb n="32" facs="tcp:179526:28"/>the effect of his laſt <hi>Vomit;</hi> fo<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> we ſuppoſe having had a ſurfeit o<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> Silk-worms, and a <hi>Loom</hi> in hi<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>Throat,</hi> he can <hi>diſgorge</hi> more at <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> caſt, than an ordinary Weave<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> can work in a weeks time. Hi<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> little <hi>pointing-ſtick</hi> and Tin Diſhes with other Implements of his Art made an horrible noiſe and <hi>com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>b<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ſtion</hi> in his Pocket, even to th<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> terrour and amazement of an <hi>Hum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble Bee,</hi> who was <hi>rioting</hi> on the Luxuries, and was wantonly <hi>bask<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing</hi> on the Sunny <hi>Terrace</hi> of a mag<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nificent Thiſtle. Nay, the jing<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling of his Tackle did alarm an Ar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>my of <hi>Waſps</hi> and <hi>Hornets,</hi> which lay <hi>encamp'd</hi> hard by under th<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> roof of a ſhady Furz buſh; Theſe made ſuch an on-ſet on Hocus with their <hi>Lanſprizades,</hi> that making a <hi>Pin-cuſhion</hi> of his Body, they ſtuck it ſo full of Needles, that the <hi>Pun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gency</hi> of their Weapons, and <hi>Ar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tillery</hi>
               <pb n="33" facs="tcp:179526:28"/>piercing to the quick, made <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>he poor fellow curvete and ele<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vate himſelf nimbly into two or <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>hree dancing <hi>Capreolls.</hi> He car<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>y'd on his back as thick a <hi>Quick<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>et</hi> of Stings as a Hog of Briſtles. He was ſwell'd to a treble propor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ion beyond what he was; his <hi>Hands</hi> were grown too big for his Pockets, and could have no re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>eption into thoſe narrow <hi>Cloſets.</hi> 
               <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>he <hi>circumference</hi> of his head was <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ugely increas'd beyond the <hi>Dia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>eter</hi> of his Hat; ſo that the <hi>Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>exity</hi> of the former could not be <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ontain'd within the <hi>Concavity</hi> of <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>he latter. In a word, being magni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>y'd beyond the <hi>fallacy</hi> of the beſt <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>laſs, his Cloaths were too little <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>or his <hi>enlarg'd</hi> Dimenſions; ſo <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>hat he burſt through the confines <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>f his <hi>ſcanty</hi> caſe. Means pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ently was us'd for the levelling of <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>his Mountainous Vagrant, and
<pb n="34" facs="tcp:179526:29"/>Hide-ſwoln; He was immedia<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly plung'd into a Bath of Hone<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> which though a preſent cure <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> his Diſeaſe and Malady, yet w<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> as great a cauſe of an inconveni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ence as bad; For a certain <hi>Be<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> not far off got his Medicine in th<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> wind, and came galloping for <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> lick of her admir'd Dainties; whi<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> when the Jugler perceiv'd, havi<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> loſt through fear the retentive F<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>culty, he adulterated her Diſh <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> a mixture of ſomewhat that w<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> of the ſame colour, though not <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> ſweet. The Jugler <hi>hooft</hi> it aw<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> with a winged ſpeed; the Be<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> with a pair up and a pair dow<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> moſt ſwiftly purſu'd him. W<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtaid not to ſee the Iſſue of t<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> Race, but advanc'd forward in regular progreſſive motion, wh<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> after a little time were croſs'd <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> a Rivulet, which wrigled alo<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> with a crooked current; ow<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <pb n="35" facs="tcp:179526:29"/>which we convey'd our ſelves by <hi>ſaltation.</hi> On the other ſide of the Bank was a little <hi>Arabia</hi> of Sand, enough (I ſuppoſe) to ſup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ply all the <hi>Hour-glaſſes</hi> in the Country, nay perhaps and that of <hi>Time</hi> too till the laſt minute; near this Mountain of Sand lay pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtrate at length <hi>two Iron</hi> Wedges contiguous to a Block in <hi>Folio,</hi> which we ſuppos'd was to be rent into collops, and to become a <hi>Sa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>crifice</hi> to hungry <hi>Vulcan.</hi> There was a numerous <hi>Family</hi> of chips about it, which were different in ſhape, colour, and bigneſs, ſo that they ſeem'd not to be the off<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpring of the ſame Parent; they lay in a <hi>Chaos</hi> without any order, amidſt which confuſion the un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lucky <hi>Gibeonite</hi> that hew'd them loſt the head of his Ax: The <hi>De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>collation</hi> whereof ſeem'd ominous to the Man, and made him ſuper<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtitiouſly
<pb n="36" facs="tcp:179526:30"/>leave his work: My <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> and a couple of <hi>Gadarens</hi> th<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> were driving Swine, made a di<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gent ſcrutiny for the <hi>Noddle</hi> 
               <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> the Tool; which after ſome ti<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> we perceiv'd to lie entomb'd und the <hi>Mauſoleum</hi> of a good luſ<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> ſhaving. We did not percei<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> that it was much damnify'd by <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> retirement, only the dampneſs <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> its <hi>
                  <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>rn</hi> did ſomewhat abate a<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> obſcure the eagerneſs of its edg<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> and the Luſtre of its Aſpect. <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> deliver'd it into the hands of <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> Owner, who preſently faſten'd <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> to the ſhoulders to which it <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> belong.</p>
            <p>After a ſmall offering of tha<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> for our careful ſearch, the Swi<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> herds turn'd to the left, and <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> wheeling to the right, after <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> had jog'd over ſome few Acre<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> a <hi>phlegmatick</hi> and cold conſtit<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, moſt happily pop'd on <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap>
               <pb n="37" facs="tcp:179526:30"/>
               <hi>warmer</hi> Turf of a pleaſant Corn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>field. 'Twas <hi>fring'd</hi> about with a Mound of Elder-trees, whoſe am<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>itious height, and luxurient Bran<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>hes gave impregnable ſecurity to <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>he neſtling Birds. The <hi>Diameter</hi> 
               <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>f a Path run through the midſt, whoſe <hi>Poles</hi> were tranſverſe or <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>hwarted the <hi>hinges</hi> of the World. 'Twas environ'd on both ſides with <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>Sea</hi> of Corn, which being mov'd <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>y the breath of <hi>Aeolus,</hi> (that Bellows of the World) what a <hi>Flux</hi> and Re-flux was there of <hi>
                  <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>aves</hi> of Wheat! We paſs'd through this Territory and Domi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nion of <hi>Ceres</hi> with the moſt exalt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>d delight. How did that <hi>Goddeſs</hi> 
               <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> in Triumph there! What crowds of <hi>Clients</hi> bowing their ears to her Commands and Dictates? Every <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>and was parted with the <hi>Iſthmus</hi> of a Balk, on ſeveral of which <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>y the <hi>Habiliments</hi> of the Har<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veſters;
<pb n="38" facs="tcp:179526:31"/>An extended ſleeve of a Red Waſt-coat, embracing the collar of a Leathern Jump, and touching the hem of a <hi>grafted</hi> Petticoat, preſented us with the Idea of a pretty <hi>Ward-Robe.</hi> We went out of this Incloſure through the weſtern paſſage of a <hi>three<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>raild</hi> Gate: Upon which there did directly ſhoot the <hi>aged</hi> Frag<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments of a <hi>decrepit</hi> wall; which over-topping our ſtature in height and tallneſs, we were forc'd to add to our quantity a Nine-inch<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtone, that raiſing our Dimenſions we might peep over it. There was ſcarce any thing remarkable on the other ſide, unleſs a vaſt Rolling-pin of humane ordure. 'Twas four Inches Diameter, and probably diſcharg'd from a <hi>Muſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ket</hi> bore, and that near upon the confines of a tuft of Wormwood, whoſe bitter ſcent mixt with the
<pb n="39" facs="tcp:179526:31"/>unſavouryneſs of <hi>Excrementitious</hi> Atoms breath'd a medly kind of ſtink, and gave but ordinary en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tertainment to our offended No<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtrils. Among the Ruines of this Mound we diſcover'd the <hi>Snout</hi> and ſome other <hi>Limbs</hi> of a <hi>mur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der'd</hi> Dial; It was not ſo defac'd, but that we could diſcover in its <hi>Phyſiognomy</hi> ſome <hi>martyr'd</hi> Figures, that were yet legible, and there were ſome Relicks of Lines, that were not quite obliterated. Time I preſume (being vext perhaps that it ſhould obſerve its motions) hath ſet its Grinders in it, and out of <hi>envy</hi> and malice hath quite de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vour'd it. I am apt to think that this pile of Stones ſtood in its Na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tive Country, where 'twas firſt bred, as may be conjectur'd from an adjacent Pillar, whoſe preg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nancy (we fancy) produc'd this <hi>litter</hi> of Stones, it being the Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther
<pb n="40" facs="tcp:179526:32"/>of theſe <hi>rockie Babes.</hi> We advanc'd to the Orifice of this <hi>La<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pideous Womb,</hi> where were hewing Mortals, by cruel <hi>Midwifery</hi> dig<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ging out the Offspring of teeming Earth. 'Twas an <hi>unpoliſh'd</hi> ſpecta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cle, and the Workmen were a<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>rough</hi> and <hi>uneven</hi> as the Proſpect<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> and the Artificers were as intra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctable and ſtubborn as the Mate<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rials, or Object of their Art. Two of the moſt <hi>Brawny</hi> Paviers ſtood lolling by the Mattock that pickt them out, and a ſingle one in a decumbent poſture lay proſtrate at their feet, whoſe Northern Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tremity perform'd the Office of a <hi>Pedeſtal</hi> to the <hi>Embryo</hi> of a Sta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tue, which was but newly hatcht, and faſhion'd in a bed of Sand<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> The Declivity of a corner near the entrance into th' Pit gave occaſion to the water to <hi>ſtagnate</hi> into <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> Puddle; through which we did
<pb n="41" facs="tcp:179526:32"/>not ſail, though the trajection was very ſhort, but fetching a circuit about its ſhore, we went out at the paſſage through which we enter'd. But no ſooner had we convey'd our ſelves out of this <hi>hole,</hi> but after we had trac'd o're ſome few Furlongs of a <hi>graſſy Pavement,</hi> a certain Moity of our Bodies pop'd into <hi>another,</hi> and a few ſteps after ſome of our feet happen'd into a third; and a lit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tle while after, falling down, our hands were buried in two more. We wonder'd who had punch'd ſo many Eyelet-holes in the Earth's skin, till ſeeing a Robin <hi>Run-a-hole</hi> ſit mumping (like a Troglodite) in his houſe under ground, we per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceiv'd the Incloſure we were in, was a well peopled <hi>Warren:</hi> We had a frisk or two after the Inha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bitants of the place; but their <hi>Heels</hi> prevented our deſign on
<pb n="42" facs="tcp:179526:33"/>their <hi>Scuts,</hi> for the nimbleneſs of the <hi>one</hi> ſecur'd them from impoſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of <hi>Salt</hi> on the <hi>other.</hi> The <hi>Sanctuary</hi> of their Burrows de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fended them from the violence of all <hi>Perſecutions.</hi> Their <hi>Cells</hi> were contiguous, nay in ſome place they had broken down the Parti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions, and by a frequent <hi>Burglary</hi> did invade the privacy of each o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thers apartments. The <hi>Dragon</hi> that kept this <hi>Garden</hi> of Coneys was a <hi>Zamzummin</hi> in ſtature, a ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cond <hi>Goliah,</hi> whoſe hand was <hi>Quarterſtafft</hi> with a mighty Bea<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>. They told us of an <hi>Hercules</hi> or two that came to encounter this Keeper, who ('tis ſaid) did ſo <hi>out-club</hi> the Yermin, that inſtead of an <hi>Auger hole,</hi> he made them earth themſelves in the Aſylum of a <hi>Coney-hole.</hi> The <hi>Burrow</hi> of the Keeper ſtood near the center of his Dominions, being the <hi>Metrop<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>litan</hi>
               <pb n="43" facs="tcp:179526:33"/>Seat of that little <hi>Nation</hi> of Rabbets. The <hi>Architecture</hi> of the Fabrick was not contemptible, being ſtately in height, whoſe top was <hi>crown'd</hi> with the magnifi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cence of <hi>Turrets,</hi> whoſe vigilant loftineſs had an eye to the ſecurity of the circumjacent Region: The biggeſt <hi>wonderment</hi> we beheld a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bout it, was, That its <hi>Head</hi> did not ſhoot ſo far <hi>upward</hi> into one Element, but its <hi>Feet</hi> ſunk as low <hi>downward</hi> into another, it ſtand<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing knee-deep, nay almoſt up to the Waſt in Earth, having as many Stories under ground as it had a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bove. Whether the Bucks or Does were the <hi>Pioneers</hi> that dug thoſe Cellars, or whether the Architect deſign'd them on purpoſe to pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vent the underminings of thoſe notable <hi>Delvers,</hi> we are not ſo well able to determine. We e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpy'd in a corner a <hi>wooden Strata<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gem</hi>
               <pb n="44" facs="tcp:179526:34"/>or two, on purpoſe to entrap (we ſuppos'd) enſnaring Rey<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nard, ſo that that living <hi>Gin,</hi> ſo fatal to Pullen, dy'd himſelf in a <hi>wile,</hi> and one <hi>Trap</hi> was <hi>trapan'd</hi> by another. 'Twas a well contriv'd <hi>Ambuſh,</hi> and pretty handſomely victual'd with a good luſty <hi>Tem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ptation,</hi> which ſo wrought upon Reynard, that he could not by any means reſiſt its charms, though 'tis thought he was as <hi>wiſe</hi> a Fox as any in <hi>Aeſop,</hi> whom we never met with, without a piece of <hi>Morality</hi> tackt to their Tails.</p>
            <p>Having paſs'd the Bounds of this <hi>Rabbet-Limbo,</hi> it was not long before we were embrac'd within the confines of a ſpot of ground like an Orchard; For the Ranges of Vegetables gave us a ſhrewd ſuſpition that <hi>Pomona</hi> had had her reſidence in that place: Here <hi>Au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tumnus</hi> ſtood lolling under the
<pb n="45" facs="tcp:179526:34"/>preſſure of a Burden, being ſcarce able to bear ſo many <hi>wreaths</hi> of Fruit. His Head was crown'd ſo, that it bow'd with Apples; ſo that ſhaking his ears as we paſs'd through, he did ſo pelt us with a <hi>ſhower,</hi> that the unlading of his <hi>Noddle</hi> made <hi>fractures</hi> in our Pates, and rais'd <hi>Tumours</hi> in <hi>ſinciput</hi> as big as Kentiſh Pippins. The place was pretty <hi>populous</hi> with Trees, the <hi>ſquadrons</hi> whereof ſeem'd to be well diſciplin'd, ſtanding in their Ranks, and as it were in <hi>Battle-array</hi> like a well order'd Army. Here were ſeveral degrees of Ve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>getables in wonderful ſubordinati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on one under another from the <hi>Commonalty</hi> of Shrubs to the <hi>Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jesty</hi> of a Cedar. Here were <hi>In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ferior</hi> and <hi>Superior,</hi> and (as it were) <hi>Dignify'd</hi> Fruit-Trees; a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mong whom there ſtood a Pear-Tree, I ſuppoſe Lord <hi>Primate</hi> of
<pb n="46" facs="tcp:179526:35"/>the <hi>Hierarchy.</hi> In a South-weſt corner we eſpy'd a few <hi>vermicula<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ting</hi> Hops, wrigling like worms up the <hi>Pyramid</hi> of a Pole; near which ſtood an Elm-Tree in the <hi>Arm<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> of Ivy, which hugg'd it ſo cloſe that it was almoſt <hi>incorporated</hi> in to it by its <hi>claſping</hi> Embraces. The <hi>Poſteriours</hi> of the Elm-Tree wen<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> moſt barbarouſly <hi>chaſtiz'd</hi> by the Prinkles of a Bramble, which the <hi>Breath</hi> of <hi>Aeolus</hi> would often mov<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> with ſmart Jerks. One of ou<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> company taking an occaſion <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> paſs by one of theſe unſeen Brian they preſently had their <hi>Talon<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> clawing upon his back, and fright<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed the Man as much as the Buſh di<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>Demonſthenes,</hi> which catching his by the Coat, made him (ſuppo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſing it to be an Enemy) to cry ou<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> for Quarter: But the Fellow being <hi>cas'd</hi> in Leather, and the <hi>Buffu<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> of his Coat being Armor-pro<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>
               <pb n="47" facs="tcp:179526:35"/>againſt the Briſtles and (as it were) <hi>Hedghogiſm</hi> of their Prickles, they could not faſten their Fangs in his Garment, wherefore (thanks to his Stars) the Man had no hurt, but was bleſs'd with a great deli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verance. Toward the bottom of this Orchard lay proſtrate the Trunk of a ſlain <hi>Myrtle,</hi> and that not far from the verge or ſhadow of a <hi>Cops</hi> of Beans, pretty tall in ſtature, and well branch'd; by the <hi>Coverlets</hi> we ſaw there ſhould be <hi>Beds</hi> not far off, I ſuppoſe they were the <hi>Lodgings</hi> of Carrots, Tur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nips, and of other Roots. There were <hi>Cabbages</hi> grown to a com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mendable <hi>globoſity,</hi> the roundneſs whereof tempted us to a Game at <hi>Foot-ball;</hi> we banded them about ſufficiently, and made ſome of them caper over a Ten-foot wall. One of the Gameſters was his juſt in the mouth, the bore whereof
<pb n="48" facs="tcp:179526:36"/>being too little for the Bullet, could not receive it into its <hi>Orifice,</hi> but however it <hi>gelded</hi> and dampt its fury, ſo that it did not retort with violence to the injury and detriment of any body elſe. We had ſweat longer at the Recreation and <hi>Olympick</hi> ſport of <hi>Kick-Cab<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bage,</hi> had not the Breath of <hi>Cloa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cina</hi> (her habitation being near) been ſo ſtrong, and been a nuſance unto us.</p>
            <p>So that being <hi>ſtunk</hi> out of our <hi>Quarters,</hi> we turn'd our <hi>Quarters</hi> upon the <hi>ſtink,</hi> and travel'd over a Grate into a Church-yard: The Track of our path lay between the <hi>Manſion houſe</hi> of the Levite on the left hand, and the <hi>Church</hi> on the right; behind which towards the South there <hi>ſtood</hi> or <hi>lay</hi> (we cannot tell which) a weather-beaten <hi>Tomb,</hi> which was <hi>Mouſe-eaten</hi> at one end by that <hi>Vermind</hi>
               <pb n="49" facs="tcp:179526:36"/>Time, that nibbles all things: It ſeem'd to be an inverted <hi>Hog-Trough</hi> turn'd topſy-turvy with its muzzle downward; but whe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther it was or not, or whether it was purpoſely erected as a <hi>Monu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment</hi> to preſerve the memory of thoſe Aſhes that lay under it, we cannot tell, tho we have ſome reaſon to ſuſpect the Former, in regard there were ſo many Swine a digging about, who with the natural <hi>Spades</hi> of their noſes, had almoſt made a <hi>Pit-hole</hi> for the <hi>Stone,</hi> and ſo had like to have bury'd <hi>one grave</hi> in another. Here was a whole <hi>Herd</hi> of Swine a rooting as if they had been turn'd in on purpoſe to root up <hi>Chriſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ans,</hi> as they are in the Feilds in <hi>Italy</hi> to dig up Turffles. A little <hi>Wall</hi> lay ſculking about this Territory of the Dead, which we ſuppos'd was plac'd
<pb n="50" facs="tcp:179526:37"/>there as a <hi>Bulwark</hi> to their Aſhes but it prov'd but a feeble Fence againſt the intruſion of the Lambs who made frequent <hi>Capreolls</hi> in to this adjacent Dormitory: The mound was rais'd a little, and cap'd with Turf, and environ'd with the hollowneſs of a good handſome Ditch; but yet, neither <hi>Cap</hi> nor Ditch could keep theſe Animals from <hi>l<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ap-frogging</hi> over them, from grazing in a <hi>Charnel</hi> houſe, and from turning a <hi>Coe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mitery</hi> of Shades and Ghoſts in to a <hi>Feeding Paſture</hi> of hungry Beaſts.</p>
            <p>We mounted this wall, an<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> mov'd on towards the Weſters period of our intended Journey The bordering cloſe was <hi>pimpled</hi> with mole-hills, which ſeem'd bu<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> young <hi>Protuberances</hi> not bliſter'<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> into the bigneſs of ſome neigh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bouring Banks. Leaving thi<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <pb n="51" facs="tcp:179526:37"/>ground behind us, we deſcended the Declivity of an adjoyning Paſture pretty well <hi>bearded</hi> or <hi>
                  <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>riſtled</hi> with Thorns and Buſhes; <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>nd ſo paſs'd through a Farmers <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ard, where we ſaw an <hi>Alps</hi> of Straw, with Swine (inſtead of Snow) a groveling a- top on't; which put us in mind of the <hi>Am<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bition</hi> of Goats, who are always clambering up the crags of Rocks. The Weſtern Extremity of the Wheat-Hovil ſhot directly up the Barn, an <hi>Appendix</hi> to which ſtood <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>he <hi>Apartment</hi> of the Hogs, over which was <hi>perch't</hi> a Rooſt for Poultry.</p>
            <p>Not far from this Country <hi>Tuſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>culum</hi> ſtood the <hi>Iſland</hi> of a houſe <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>n the embraces of a Moat, like Ticho's <hi>
                  <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>ranoberg</hi> in the midſt of the Sea; An antient Pile, a Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verend <hi>Neſt</hi> of as Venerable a <hi>Bird,</hi> which having taken her Flight
<pb n="52" facs="tcp:179526:38"/>hath left it a ſolitude. The great<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eſt Obſervables were a little ſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lent <hi>Bell</hi> in <hi>Duodecimo,</hi> which be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing utterly <hi>Diſleepled,</hi> hung be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tween the collops of an old wa<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> or rather a <hi>Mortar</hi> invers'd, whic<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> had loſt its Peſtle, ſo that it wi<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> not vocal by ſtroke of <hi>intern<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> Clapper,</hi> but by knocks and blow of <hi>external Hammer;</hi> within th<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> found of this Bell ſtood a lolli<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>waſhing-Block;</hi> being a woodd<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> kind of <hi>Anvil,</hi> where the <hi>S<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap> Vulcans</hi> were <hi>hammering</hi> out wit<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> Battle-Door the Filth of Linne<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> whoſe unctuous Diſtillations we<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> the <hi>Nile</hi> that water'd the litt<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>Egypt</hi> of the adjacent garden.</p>
            <p>Having mov'd from this Ma<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſion about three or four Furlon<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> we paſs'd by the skirts of a <hi>rota<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap> Engine,</hi> in ſhape not unlike <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> Houſe, being <hi>pack-ſall'd</hi> at T'<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> with a aridge: it ſeem'd to ſta<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>
               <pb n="53" facs="tcp:179526:38"/>upon ſtilts, and to be a moving Habitation like thoſe of the <hi>Getes.</hi> 'Twas <hi>prefac'd</hi> with a <hi>Portico,</hi> in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to which we aſcended by a ſcale of Stairs. The whiſtling Wind breath'd a <hi>Vertigo</hi> in its Pate, whoſe giddyneſs communicating a motion to its Grinders, made it <hi>whirlegig</hi> the grain into Flow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>er. A little diſtant from hence beyond a ſmall ſandy Deſert ſtood a Village, whoſe <hi>Steeple</hi> was in its center, not unlike the <hi>Maſt</hi> of a Ship. This Tower as to out<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ward appearance had a <hi>Portly Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon:</hi> yet they told us it had the imperfection of Dumbneſs; it having been <hi>Diſ bell'd</hi> for ſome years. They were alarm'd to Church by the Report of a <hi>Mus<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ket,</hi> which the Clerk (being an eminent <hi>Guner</hi>) did uſually diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>charge at every mans Door. This Clerk was a <hi>Weaver</hi> by Trade,
<pb n="54" facs="tcp:179526:39"/>and had relation to a <hi>Loom,</hi> where in he had been <hi>ambling</hi> for ſeve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ral years with one Foot <hi>up</hi> an<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> the other <hi>down,</hi> and with all <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> treading hath ſcarce got clo<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> enough to repair the Breaches <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> his tatter'd Elbows. They to<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> us that his Trade and he had lat<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly been at <hi>Cuffs,</hi> and are juſt u<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on parting, it being ſuch a <hi>Lim<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> wagging</hi> Profeſſion, that he is no<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>able to endure the <hi>Pennance</hi> 
               <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> it. This man had wonderful ski<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> in <hi>ſweeping</hi> the Church, and 'ti<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> thought could tell what a <hi>Clo<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> 'twas at the <hi>South</hi> Dial as well <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> moſt <hi>Aſtronomers;</hi> He was alſo <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> pretty Man of <hi>his hands</hi> for <hi>ſing<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing;</hi> For when the Tune one Su<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>day had <hi>ambled</hi> from him into th<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> Chancel, and had almoſt caugh a fall among the <hi>Non-ſongſters</hi> really they told us that this <hi>N<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>table Man</hi> gave it ſuch a ne<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <pb n="55" facs="tcp:179526:39"/>
               <hi>jerk,</hi> as that he <hi>twitch</hi> it into the Church ſtrangely. Now (I ſay.) for the Clerk to have a rare knack of ſecuring the <hi>Hymn</hi> from thoſe that would ſteal it, Oh! Tis an execllent thing! The moſt remar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>kable things in this Town were an <hi>Eccleſiastical</hi> Wall made of <hi>Soe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cular</hi> Mud, which mounded in the Introduction of the Parſonage: it afforded ſecure Harbour to <hi>Va<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>grant Bees,</hi> who randevozing here, became a <hi>Colony;</hi> They made ſo many Cells in it, that it appear'd to be the Fragment a Reverend <hi>Hony-Comb.</hi> Not far from this grew a Tree in <hi>Folio,</hi> an huge, thick, ſquot Elm, <hi>pounded</hi> with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in the circumferences of 4 Benches, which we ſuppos'd to be ſeats made a purpoſe for the <hi>Poſterns</hi> of Specta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tors, when <hi>Whitſun-Ale</hi> is ſolemniz'd with <hi>Feſtivity</hi> of Fiddle, and cele<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>brated with <hi>Caper</hi> after Pipe and Tabour.</p>
            <pb n="56" facs="tcp:179526:40"/>
            <p>Immediately after our Depa<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ture from this place, night ove<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>took us, whoſe <hi>Sables</hi> eclipſing th<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> Splendor of the Day, ſhortne<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> our courſe, and <hi>crooken'd</hi> our Ca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>reer aſide to look for a Lodgin<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> An happy <hi>Retroſpect</hi> oblig'd <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> with the <hi>Proſpect</hi> of <hi>glimmerin<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> Thatch, which the nearer we ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>proacht, the more viſibly it a<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pear'd in the ſhape of an <hi>Houſe.</hi> 
               <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> was call'd by way of Irony a <hi>Caſ<gap reason="illegible" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> whoſe Governour was a decay <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>Taylor,</hi> who having loſt throug<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> an <hi>unfortunate</hi> hole of his Pocken his Needles, Thimble, thoſe <hi>Cha<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tels</hi> of his Breeches, and Imple<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments of his Vocation, was re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>duc'd to poverty. The Man wa<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>nimble</hi> of <hi>foot,</hi> though a <hi>Dwarf</hi> 
               <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>bulk,</hi> ſo that nine of ſuch mig<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> very well club to the <hi>elementing</hi> 
               <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> a Man. After a ſmall Collation a <hi>Tripe</hi> and <hi>Buttermilk,</hi> we tript <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap>
               <pb n="57" facs="tcp:179526:40"/>a Ladder to the apartments of our ſeveral Cabbins, where with the <hi>Poppies</hi> of ſleep we refreſht our Noddles to the great comfort and ſatisfaction of our wearied Car<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>kaſſes. After Valediction to Prick<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>louſe, the next morning we ſet out with the Sun, and had not went above a mile or two, but we heard the rumor of a ſad <hi>diſaster</hi> which had lately befaln a Country <hi>Corydon,</hi> which was the loſs of a whole pound of Candles, ſuppos'd to be ſtoln by ſome <hi>high-way</hi> Rat at one <hi>Robbery.</hi> The Relations were various as to the manner of the theft; ſome ſay he carry'd them away behind him like a <hi>bur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>den</hi> of ſticks; others ſay, that he hung them by his ſide like <hi>Bandi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>leers,</hi> but moſt agree that he laid them upon his ſhoulder one by one, and ran arm'd away with the Luminaries as with ſo many Muſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>kets.
<pb n="58" facs="tcp:179526:41"/>We were ſomewhat amaz<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>d at the horror of that ſad ſtory, fearing leſt we our ſelves ſhould be a <hi>Prey</hi> to thoſe bold <hi>Banditi,</hi> who being pretty <hi>greaſie,</hi> ſeem'd to be a good handſome <hi>Bait,</hi> and ſo being miſtaken for <hi>Rats-bane</hi> might be <hi>pouch'd</hi> by the Vermin: But (thanks to the Stars) we e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcap'd the Fate of the <hi>Biſhop</hi> 
               <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>Mentz,</hi> and march'd on upon the <hi>Fore-head</hi> of a ſmooth Mountain upon the ſummity whereof <hi>ſquo<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted</hi> another Hill; but it bore n<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> proportion to the ſeat it ſate on being but a <hi>Pimple</hi> to it, as tha<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> was but a <hi>Mole-hill</hi> to the whol<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> Globe; it put us in mind of <hi>P<gap reason="illegible" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lion</hi> clambering upon the back <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>Oſſa,</hi> that falſe <hi>Heraldry</hi> of th<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> Giants, Hill upon Hill, by whic<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> Bunches they thought to hav<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> ſcal'd Heaven; the <hi>Crown</hi> of th<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> uppermoſt was ſomewhat depre<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>
               <pb n="59" facs="tcp:179526:41"/>and ſunk into the <hi>hollowneſs</hi> of a little Valley, about which ſtood the natural <hi>Banniſters</hi> of ſome Thorn-buſhes, whoſe folding Bran<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ches weav'd into a <hi>Lattice,</hi> which <hi>threaded</hi> by the Sun-beams <hi>dappled</hi> the ground with a pleaſant <hi>chec<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quer-work,</hi> and yielded beſides a good handſome ſhade to the pant<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing Sheep, whoſe Fleeces diſcover'd them to have taken ſanctuary here a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt the <hi>Perſecutions</hi> of the violent heat; for the Cattle feeding within the covert, and ruſhing through the Brake, every Briar took <hi>Toll</hi> of their Coats, and <hi>excis'd</hi> their Backs as faſt as they fill'd their Bellies; on every ſpring there hung a Fragment of their <hi>Liveries,</hi> and the whole hedge was <hi>cloath'd</hi> with tatter'd Fleeces, as if Wooll had been <hi>vegetable</hi> and had grown there. Theſe <hi>ſpoils</hi> were lookt upon as excellent Booty to vagrant Youth, who went about ſtripping,
<pb n="60" facs="tcp:179526:42"/>plundering, and (as it were <hi>Sheep ſhearing</hi> the hedges: W<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> met a crew of theſe <hi>Pickeerin<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> Wool-gatherers, the very <hi>Emblem<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> of Beggery, and but once remov'<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> from vileſt <hi>Raſcality;</hi> one Shoo<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> a-piece, and half a Hat, a <hi>Rem<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>nant</hi> of a Doublet, and a <hi>Moiety</hi> 
               <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> a Sleeve, a pair of <hi>Diſpocket</hi> Bre<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ches, and a <hi>jagged</hi> Jump, wen<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> the flower of their Accoutrements except two or three locks of Wo<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> tuck'd like Scuts under their Gir<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>dles as a <hi>Badge</hi> of their profeſſion and ſome cram'd Stockins <hi>bobbin<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> at their ſides as <hi>Trophies</hi> of thei<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> Pyracies.</p>
            <p>Some few Furlongs from hen<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> there was a <hi>mixt Aſſembly</hi> of Ki<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> and Goats at dinner upon th<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>Lawns;</hi> their Meal was interrup<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ed by the unwelcome ſalutes <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> troubleſome Breeze, whoſe <hi>ſtim<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>lation</hi> of Rump did engender ſuc<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <pb n="61" facs="tcp:179526:42"/>a Frolick, that with <hi>curled</hi> Tail and toſs'd-up Horn they run gad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding and bellowing, and with their vocal Friskings, with a plea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſant kind of terror, did at once both <hi>recreate</hi> and affright the aſto<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſh'd Beholders: The Magiſtrate or <hi>Herds-man,</hi> that kept theſe A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nimals, was in the midſt of the Tumult, who finding himſelf miſerably involv'd in a <hi>Hubbub,</hi> with furious Club chaſtiz'd their Gameſomneſs, and with mighty buſſing becalm'd the uproar. This Fellow was a ſtrange Creature, wonderfully <hi>Goth'd,</hi> and <hi>all-to-be-Vandall'd</hi> even to Barbarity it ſelf. A Clown in grain! An uncultiva<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted Boor! A Beaſt of the Herd in humane ſhape. We propos'd a Quaery or two about the <hi>Genius</hi> of the Place; he told us the Soil was cold, and big with <hi>clay,</hi> and would doubtleſs yield a good
<pb n="62" facs="tcp:179526:43"/>
               <hi>Harveſt</hi> of Tobacco-pipes: And as for the People, he ſaid they were a <hi>Pan-pudding</hi> ſort of People, much addicted to that vile ſort of Creature. A whole Table at a Chriſtening is ſpread with a <hi>Yard</hi> of <hi>Pudding,</hi> and a <hi>Balk</hi> of Beef, a <hi>Ridge</hi> of one and a <hi>Furrow</hi> of the other, which did ſo wonderfully work upon their Chops, and made their mouths ſo water, that two of the chiefeſt <hi>Grandees</hi> of the Town, the <hi>Hogherd</hi> and the <hi>Hey<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ward</hi> fell ſeriouſly to ſnouting for ſome few Morſels: the <hi>two-ear'd</hi> Pitcher that ſtood upon the Bench was Mr. <hi>Prinn'd</hi> in the ſcuffle, <hi>i. e.</hi> loſt a Lug in the Fray; and we were inform'd afterward that the <hi>Diſtaff</hi> loſt a Lock or two of its Flaxen <hi>Periwig.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Among <hi>Rational</hi> wonders the moſt remarkable Miracle of this Place, was an eminent <hi>Cot-quean,</hi>
               <pb n="63" facs="tcp:179526:43"/>a <hi>meer</hi> Woman in the habit of a <hi>Man,</hi> a kind of <hi>Mal-cut-purs'd</hi> Creature, an <hi>Epicaene</hi> Animal of a <hi>twisted</hi> Gender, who hath a <hi>Pet<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ticoat</hi> Soul in a <hi>Trunk-Breech'd</hi> Bo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dy, and ſcandalizeth <hi>Virility</hi> by skill in <hi>Houſewifery.</hi> He ſpins (they ſay) like a Spider, and makes his Wheel giddy by a ſwift <hi>Vertigo;</hi> we obſerv'd him to be <hi>ſtately</hi> in his gate when he advan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceth up to Spindle; and indeed was <hi>retrograde</hi> again with no little <hi>Gravity.</hi> He is a learned <hi>Crafts<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man</hi> in the making of Diet, a no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>table <hi>Food-Framer,</hi> who buffets the Cream till he hath <hi>frighted</hi> it <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>nto a conſiſtence, and knock'd it <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>nto Butter, and afterward ſquee<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>zes with dexterity of Fiſt. He was endow'd with the gift of toſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſing of Pan-cakes, and had a won<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>derful knack at tempering the Materials of a Bag-pudding. He
<pb n="64" facs="tcp:179526:44"/>ſurpaſs'd the Dairy-maids in <hi>Mil<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>-pan</hi> accompliſhments, and was e<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>cellently qualified for a Meal-Tu<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> Office. He ſqueez'd the Curd<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> with <hi>Cheeſe-preſs</hi> Bum, and knea<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> the Dough with fulch of Elbo<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> He is a <hi>Critick</hi> at ſweeping, an<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> manageth the Beeſome with mig<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ty skill. We could hardly diſce<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> any more of duſt, he having <hi>di<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>lodg'd</hi> from Crevis even the ſma<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>leſt Atoms; we were dazled wit<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> the <hi>Sun-ſhine</hi> of his radiant <hi>Braſs</hi> which was exceedingly enlighten'<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> by <hi>modern</hi> cleanſing, he being <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> ſingular ſcowrer, and very know<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ing and able at Sand and <hi>Oiſte<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ſhel.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>This <hi>Hen-Houſ wife</hi>-Mortal liv'<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> a monkiſh kind of Life, bein<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> cloiſter'd up in a deſolate habit<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>tion of a certain Gentleman, who we ſuppoſe, does fee him to dwe<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> there to affright the Mice, and <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap>
               <pb n="65" facs="tcp:179526:44"/>be a <hi>Bull-beggar</hi> to the Rats; and alſo to terrifie a worſe kind of <hi>Vermin</hi> which we call <hi>Theeves,</hi> who are apt to creep through the <hi>Mouſe-hole</hi> of a window, and to <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ibble away the Furniture of a diſpoſſeſt houſe: or poſſibly he might abide there to repair its <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>reaches, and to recover it from <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ts crazineſs, and by the whole<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ome <hi>Phyſick</hi> of frequent Fires to <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>eep it in <hi>health,</hi> and to perſwade <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>t not to tumble, but to remain till a Manſion to the Family that <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>wns it.</p>
            <p>We taſted here of the Hoſpita<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>ty of this fœmaſculine wight, <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ho ſpread a Joynt-ſtool with ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>eral ſorts of Viands; which <gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>ough not very <hi>delicate,</hi> yet the <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ariety might atone and make a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ends for their <hi>meanneſs.</hi> Here <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>as the <hi>Epidermis</hi> of a Hog, the <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>utward skin call'd the <hi>Swerd</hi> of
<pb n="66" facs="tcp:179526:45"/>Bacon, which was infected with the Jaundice, and look'd yellow<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> here was the Hull of a Peſco<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> plunder'd of its Peaſe, and corn'<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> with Salt, ſome broken Fragmen<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> of Sheeps Trotters S. <hi>Lawrenc</hi>'<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> on a Gridiron; the offal of <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> Lark, the minc'd Spurs of a <hi>Boo<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>leſs</hi> Cock, a skim'd Quadrant <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> ſoft Cheeſe, well ſawc'd with th<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>Butt-ends</hi> of forked Scallions, th<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> mouldy reverſion of an <hi>Antiquate<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> Loaf dipt in the verdure of W<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ter-creſſe Pottage, afforded us th<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> refreſhment of a pretty Collatio<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> by the vertue whereof being ſome what recruited, we mov'd for ward and crep up the <hi>Brisket</hi> of ſmall Mountain, upon whoſe ſloa<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ing deſcent ſtood a Quadrangula<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>Sheep-pen,</hi> which we paſs'd throug<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> and found pitcht with <hi>Buttons,</hi> 
               <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> pretty ſort of Floor and Mode<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>Moſaick.</hi> Not far from the mo<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>
               <pb n="67" facs="tcp:179526:45"/>eaſtern hurdle (as near as we could obſerve) lean'd a ruinous Bridge, which glory'd in the paſſage but of one Arch, and that ſeem'd ra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther <hi>Natural</hi> than <hi>Artificial;</hi> for the Impetuoſity of the Current having bor'd an hole through a heap of ſtones, lick'd it into the ſhape of an indifferent Arch: At the Foot whereof ſtood a Smiths Shop, about a Bay of watling; <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>t ſeem'd to be a pretty reverend Seat as we gather'd from the Man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tle of Green Moſs upon its back. Though it was cover'd with ſtub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble <hi>without,</hi> yet it was pretty to<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>erably furniſh'd with Iron <hi>within,</hi> 
               <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>s thread-bare Horſe-ſhooes, bits of Keys, ſome few ſemicircles of <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ron Rings, odd Links of <hi>interru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ted</hi> Fetters, and a broken <hi>Series</hi> of a diſcontinued Chain. The <hi>Vulcan</hi> was in his Den, and was <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ammering out Hob-nails for
<pb n="68" facs="tcp:179526:46"/>Countrey hoof. His Forge w<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> rais'd from the ground like an A<hi>
                  <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>tar,</hi> upon which there did bur<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> (as it were) a <hi>Veſtal</hi> Fire, whi<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> blaſt of Bellows made much <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> bubble up in this little <hi>Mongib<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> What Cinders were belch'd fro<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> this flaming <hi>Veſuvius,</hi> whoſe ſmo<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> and aſhes beſmutted the <hi>Pluto</hi> 
               <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> this Infernal Region! who havi<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> Primitive Apparel, <hi>i. e.</hi> bei<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>skin'd</hi> over with a Caſe of <hi>Leath<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> and having a ſwarthy Complex<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>on, did with the <hi>grimneſs</hi> of <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> Aſpect, and with the horrib<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>ruſſel</hi> of his Breeches, fright o<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> of the Dogs of our company i<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> a fit of ſickneſs; we imagin'd <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> Cur might miſtake him for a <hi>T<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ker,</hi> who is commonly a <hi>Diſe<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> or at leaſt a <hi>Nuſance</hi> to thoſe Cr<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>tures.</p>
            <p>We ſaw nothing hereabouts v<gap reason="illegible" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap> remarkable, only we met ſeve<gap reason="illegible" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap>
               <pb n="69" facs="tcp:179526:46"/>Maſtiffs laden with the <hi>Cargo</hi> of good luſty Bones in their mouths; they were ambling eaſtward; a very fine ſpectacle to ſee a Regi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of Curs trooping along in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtead of <hi>Bilboa,</hi> arm'd with <hi>Shoul<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der-blades.</hi> We wonder'd at firſt from whence ſuch plenty of <hi>Ana<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tomy</hi> as to furniſh them, till ſpy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing the Carkaſs of a dead Palfry, we perceiv'd they had been feaſt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed with the Viands of his Fleſh, and ſtole the Skeleton Piece-meal. A Baker chanc'd to come by through a Gap near at hand, mounted upon juſt ſuch another <hi>Morſel,</hi> ripe for Collar-maker, which being ſurpriz'd with the ſpe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctacle of his Brother <hi>Carrion,</hi> took an occaſion to ſtart, and to diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>burden himſelf of his Load; which ſad misfortune prov'd a lucky acci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dent to the Dogs, whereby they were furniſh'd with <hi>Bread</hi> to their Meat.</p>
            <pb n="70" facs="tcp:179526:47"/>
            <p>Not far from hence was a ſcu<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> Slough, moſt fatal (as is obſerv<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> to Millers, whom it ſups up i<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> the <hi>Abyſſe</hi> of its profundity; <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> ſaw one moving <hi>a-tit-up, a-tit-<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> till he flounc'd in, and by a m<gap reason="illegible" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap> diſaſtrous <hi>Pitch-pole</hi> into mud a<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> dirt, diſcolour'd his Coat, th<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> was candy'd with the <hi>effluviums <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> his mealy Bags. The <hi>Neck-lace</hi> 
               <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> Bells about the creſt of his Be<gap reason="illegible" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap> ceas'd to be ſonorous, being qui<gap reason="illegible" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap> choak'd. His Meal through frig<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> and moiſture was metamorpho<gap reason="illegible" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap> into Pudding; and ſpunging <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> the Liquos, it grew ſo heav<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> that it <hi>thriv'd</hi> into ſuch unweil<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>neſs, as that it was almoſt <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> moveable: we cautelouſly wa<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> the danger of this dirt by dive<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ing a little toward the northe<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> parts of this Quagmire, and ſo <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> a dainty fine Path, and that <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> meanly beautify'd with vari<gap reason="illegible" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap>
               <pb n="71" facs="tcp:179526:47"/>of Flowers, we continu'd our <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ourney very proſperouſly, only <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ne of our company had a moſt calamitous fall over an unhappy clod of the <hi>first magnitude,</hi> which undermining his Pedeſtals, gave him a prepoſterous <hi>ſquob,</hi> his head ſaluting the ground firſt, to the great detriment of the <hi>outward man.</hi> There run parallel with this Path a pitcht Cauſey (as we ſuppos'd) about ten Furlongs, we ſtept into it, and follow'd its track till it brought us into the deſert of a Common, not ſo much as ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>commodated with Horſe, Tree, Houſe, or Man, ſo that here we felt the rigour of ſomewhat call'd harſhip, the Stomack barking, the Hoof galling, the Winds whi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtling, and the Heavens dropping; all theſe conſpir'd to make us mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſerable. At laſt arriving to the borders of the Wilderneſs, we were
<pb n="72" facs="tcp:179526:48"/>courteouſly receiv'd into an h<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ſpitable Hamlet, where we enjoy <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> the bleſſing of an indifferent r<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>freſhment. We took up our Qua<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ters here that night, and paſs <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> away the evening in ſome pert<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>nent Quæries about obſervables <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> the Place. They preſented <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> with a <hi>pretty curioſity</hi> which ſeldo<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> occurs, and that was the Copy <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> a Brief containing the Loſſes of <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> diſtreſſed Virgin, which beca<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> the form and ſtile is ſomewhat <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> uſual, we care not much if <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> here inſert.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="brief">
            <pb n="73" facs="tcp:179526:48"/>
            <head>The Copy of a <hi>BRIEF.</hi>
            </head>
            <head type="sub">To all Ladies, Gentlewomen; whe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Maids, Wives or Widows, or others of that ſofter Sex, of what ſtate and condition ſoe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver, whether Waiting-women, Semſtreſſes, Spinſters, Bawds, Punks, Doxies, and all other Petticoateers, from thoſe who through <hi>wantonneſs</hi> have naked <hi>Backs</hi> to thoſe who through <hi>want</hi> have naked <hi>Bums,</hi> Greeting.</head>
            <p>
               <hi>WHereas we are credibly in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>form'd by our truſty and well-beloved</hi> Roger Thwickwack <hi>of</hi> B. <hi>in the County of</hi> Salop <hi>Jumper, and</hi> Arthur Twitch-box, <hi>Smoaker,</hi> Cadwallader Whipwhop, <hi>Wreſtler,</hi> Anthony Snug, <hi>Fidler,</hi> Giles Firker <hi>Bum-bruſher, and ſeveral others of
<pb n="74" facs="tcp:179526:49"/>the like Laudable</hi> Profeſſions; <hi>Tha<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> our beloved Subject Mrs.</hi> A. C. <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>the Town and County aforeſaid Dam<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ſel, hath lately ſuſtain'd a great loſ<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> by a most lamentable misfortune which on the fifth of this inſtan<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> moſt miſerably befell her after thi<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> manner following.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>There was a certain Glaſs-caſe <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> a</hi> Gad-fly <hi>colour,</hi> i. e. <hi>a little in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>clining to a Calf-dung Yellow, an<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> ſomewhat of a dwarfiſh ſize, no<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> much exceeding the ſtature of <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> Cricket; it was ſupported by th<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> ſtrength of a double Thong at th<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> North-weſt <hi>Point of her Chambe<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> where for ſometime it had continu<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap> in a</hi> pendulous <hi>poſture, and ha<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> arriv'd to a great repute of</hi> civility <hi>and meekneſs, whereby it did muc<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> exceed, and frequently put to th' blu<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap> the other <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>tenſils of her Chamber.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Now this Poor Thing, by reaſon <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> the rudeneſs of two</hi> luſty Puſſe<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <pb n="75" facs="tcp:179526:49"/>
               <hi>whether affrighted at their</hi> Cater<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wawling, <hi>or it being not able to bear them in the</hi> Acts of Love, <hi>we can<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>not tell, but certain it is, it let go its hold, and after a diſmal manner came blundering down, attended with the</hi> ruine <hi>and deſolation of ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veral</hi> Jiggumbobs <hi>and Jimcracks, to the great loſs and detriment of our poor diſtreſſed Subject. — The Parti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>culars whereof are as follow.</hi>
            </p>
            <list>
               <item>1. <hi>The Ivory</hi> Gums <hi>of a</hi> Tooth<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>leſs <hi>Comb.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>2. <hi>A little</hi> Bottle-breecht <hi>Glaſs, repleniſh'd with</hi> Love-Powder.</item>
               <item>3. <hi>A Brace of</hi> blind <hi>Needles that loſt their</hi> Eyes <hi>in the tumble.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>4. <hi>A</hi> Double <hi>Scut of an Hare ty'd up with a</hi> ſingle <hi>Pack-thread.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>5. <hi>The</hi> latter end <hi>of an old Broomſtaff.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>6. <hi>The</hi> Butt-end <hi>of an old Sugar-loaf.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>7. <hi>The True-Lovers</hi> Knot <hi>made in wire.</hi>
               </item>
               <pb n="76" facs="tcp:179526:50"/>
               <item>8. <hi>A ſquare bit of Tin.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>9. <hi>The Margin of a broad Hat.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>10. <hi>One Finger-stall.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>11. <hi>Two Tags.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>12. <hi>A crackt Glaſs with a club-foot.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>13. <hi>The skin of an Onion stuff<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                        <desc>••</desc>
                     </gap> with Arſenick.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>14. <hi>One</hi> Whisker <hi>of a</hi> Bearded <hi>Arrow.</hi> — <hi>The loſs of which Tackle and Implements amounting to a Sum of great value, we do ſend our Let<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ters Patents to beg the Charitable Be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nevolence of all well-diſpos'd Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons, hoping that they will be pleas'd to take the</hi> deplorable <hi>condition of our unhappy Subject into their</hi> ſeri<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ous <hi>conſideration:</hi> — <hi>For is it not <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> ſad thing to loſe ſo commodious <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> Place to lay pretty things in, and al<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> by the miſdemeanour of two</hi> unman<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>nerly Cats? <hi>For where will this ou<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> Subject lay her</hi> Gally-pots <hi>and Sy<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>rups, her Gums and Pomatum<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
                     <pb n="77" facs="tcp:179526:50"/>Had theſe</hi> Mount-hunters <hi>only eas'd Nature there, and then gingerly de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>parted, they had been very excuſable; but firſt to come</hi> ſlyly <hi>into a Ladies Chamber, and then to</hi> ſquobble <hi>and fall out there, and the midſt of their Quarrel to</hi> purſue <hi>one another to the top of a Shelf, and there to</hi> renew <hi>the Battle again, and to</hi> box <hi>one a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nother till themſelves did fall, and to demoliſh that very thing which ſupported them in their bickering; as the</hi> Fool <hi>in the Fable ſaw'd off the Bough he ſate on. Oh! this is a ſad thing.</hi>
               </item>
            </list>
            <p>
               <hi>Another</hi> Living obſervable <hi>we met with here was the</hi> Fragment <hi>of a Phyſitian, whoſe pretences to Learn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing were very great, but by converſe we found him to have more</hi> Stomack <hi>than</hi> Brains, <hi>and therefore was like to have more conſolation in a</hi> Kitchin <hi>than in a</hi> Study; <hi>for there perhaps he may find a</hi> job <hi>of work for
<pb n="78" facs="tcp:179526:51"/>his</hi> Grinders; <hi>whereas he knows no<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> what to do with his</hi> Books, <hi>unleſs h<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> ſhould act the Moth, and</hi> eat <hi>the<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> One of our Company perceiv'd hi<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> Parts to lie more towards the</hi> Pow<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>dering-tub, <hi>than his</hi> Pharmacopeia<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>for whilſt he is buſie in the</hi> former <hi>h<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> may keep himſelf</hi> alive, <hi>but when h<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> reads in the</hi> latter <hi>he kills his Pa<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>tients. We had ſome Roſt-beef t<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> Supper, and we commonly foun<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> him within an inch of the Dripping pan, with an</hi> Acre of <hi>Bread in hi<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> hand, which he call'd a Sop, wit<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> which, when our backs were turn'd he uſually ſpung'd up the Dripping and cheated Sir-Loin, and robb'd its Knighthood of its due moiſture A Scholar of our Company perceiv'd him to be well read in Papers tha<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> skreen the Back of a Limb of Roſt<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> and that he found a great deal o<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> matter in the</hi> Socks <hi>that are on th<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> Souls of Mince-pies.</hi>
            </p>
            <pb n="79" facs="tcp:179526:51"/>
            <p>After a days Journey from hence, we ſet our Feet upon <hi>Welch Turf,</hi> and indeed were ſtrangely ſurpriz'd at the <hi>uncouth<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs</hi> of many things that did ſalute us here.</p>
            <p>The Countrey is <hi>tuckt</hi> in on all ſides with the Sea, except on the Eaſt, on which part it was <hi>ditcht</hi> in from <hi>England</hi> by that <hi>notable Delver</hi> King <hi>Offa,</hi> King of the <hi>Mercians:</hi> Over this Dike if any Welch-man chance to skip with his Sword by his ſide, by King <hi>Harolds</hi> Law, he was to loſe a <hi>Branch</hi> of his Body, <hi>i. e.</hi> his right Arm was lopt off by the Kings Officers.</p>
            <p>Some think it had its Name from its <hi>God-father Idwallo</hi> Son to <hi>Cadwallader,</hi> who with a ſmall crew of <hi>Brittons</hi> at the arrival of the <hi>Saxons</hi> hid themſelves in this Corner. Others ſuppoſe them to
<pb n="80" facs="tcp:179526:52"/>be the <hi>Spawn</hi> of the <hi>Gauls,</hi> from whom they ſeem to be but a few <hi>Aps</hi> remov'd; Ap <hi>Galloys</hi> Ap <hi>Gauls,</hi> Ap <hi>Wallois</hi> Ap <hi>Wales.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>As for the <hi>Inhabitants,</hi> they are a pretty ſort of Creatures, which when we ſaw, we were ſo far from <hi>ſtroaking</hi> them with the <hi>Palms</hi> of Love, that we were al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>moſt ready to <hi>buffet</hi> them with the <hi>Fiſt</hi> of Indignation. They are a <hi>rude</hi> People, and want much <hi>In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtruction.</hi> For when we conſider the <hi>Soil</hi> from whence they <hi>ſprang,</hi> and the <hi>Deſerts</hi> and Mountains wherein they <hi>wander,</hi> we cannot but think that greater pains ſhould be taken in cultivating and manu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ring, in diſciplining and taming them, in regard 'tis harder for a <hi>Bearnard</hi> to teach civility to the <hi>Beaſts</hi> of <hi>Africa,</hi> than to thoſe that come from a more <hi>mannerly</hi> Country: — We do not ſay that
<pb n="81" facs="tcp:179526:52"/>when they are in their Countrey they do (like Bears and Foxes) live in Woods and Foreſts, (for I preſume they have more <hi>Sun</hi> than <hi>Shade,</hi> and ſo more <hi>Fire</hi> than <hi>Wood</hi>) but if we agree with <hi>Geo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>graphers,</hi> and are of an opinion that they are Inhabitants of a <hi>Wil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>derneſs,</hi> and are <hi>Landlords</hi> of a Common, as I and every body elſe are owners of the Air, we muſt beg their pardon for our conceit. We have been inform'd that they were dug from a <hi>Quarry,</hi> and that they dwell in a <hi>ſtony</hi> Land; ſo that if we compare this Kingdom to a <hi>Man;</hi> (as ſome do <hi>Italy</hi> to a Man's <hi>Leg</hi>) they inhabit the very <hi>Teſticles</hi> of the Nation. And I pray what are thoſe but the vileſt of Creatures that breed as well in the <hi>Privities</hi> of the <hi>greater</hi> Brittiſh World, as thoſe that are hatcht in the <hi>Pudenda</hi> of the leſſer? But
<pb n="82" facs="tcp:179526:53"/>whether Welch-men are the <hi>Al<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> origines</hi> of their Countrey, <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> Crab-lice are the <hi>Autocthones</hi> 
               <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> theirs, and proceed only (li<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> them) from the <hi>excrements</hi> 
               <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> their Soil, we ſhall not here d<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ſpute. They are of a <hi>Bcoriſh</hi> be<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>haviour, of a <hi>Savage</hi> Phyſiogn<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>my; the <hi>ſhabbineſs</hi> of their B<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>dies, and the <hi>Baoticalneſs</hi> of the<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> Souls, and that, which cannot a<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> otherwiſe be expreſt, the <hi>Welchneſ<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> of both, will fright a Man as fa<gap reason="illegible" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap> from them, as the <hi>odneſs</hi> of the<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> Perſons invites one to behol<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> them. Some of them are ſuc<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>rude</hi> and <hi>indigeſted</hi> Lumps, ſo <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> from being <hi>Men,</hi> that they <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> ſcarce be advanc'd into <hi>Livi<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> Creatures; nay they are ſuch u<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>manageable <hi>Materials</hi> that they <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> ſcarce be hewn into the ſhape <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>Blocks;</hi> much Labour and Art <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> requir'd therefore to make the<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>Statues.</hi>
            </p>
            <pb n="83" facs="tcp:179526:53"/>
            <p>They are not much given to <hi>fighting,</hi> as by a Speech it appears that was utter'd by hur nown Country-man, who when drawn out upon ſome Deſign, began to <hi>pur</hi> and murmur after this manner.</p>
            <p>
               <q rend="margQuotes">Hur hath worn out her Freez <hi>Preeches,</hi> and all hur Cloaths; and now hur can get no Money to keep hur, or to buy hur ſome <hi>Cows-baby,</hi> and hur could hear nothing but <hi>Marſh, Marſh!</hi> and Drums beat, hur was therefore (once for all) now reſolv'd to fight no longer, but to go into hur nown Countrey.</q> — They are much inclin'd to <hi>Choler;</hi> for hur Welch Plood is ſoon mov'd, and then hur <hi>ſtamp</hi> and <hi>ſtare,</hi> and ſcrat hur Pole, and vent hur fury in <hi>ud-plutter-a-nails,</hi> and will fight for hur life in battle at Fiſty-cuffs.</p>
            <p>The whole Nation (like a <hi>Ger<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man</hi> Family) is of one <hi>Quality;</hi>
               <pb n="84" facs="tcp:179526:54"/>for as every Lords Son is a <hi>Lor<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> here,</hi> ſo every one is crown'd will the Title of <hi>Gentleman there;</hi> ſ<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> that hur Countrey is a good <hi>Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſture</hi> for an <hi>Herald</hi> to bite in. Wh<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> can't chooſe but grow <hi>fat</hi> among ſuch worſhipful <hi>Genealogies.</hi> W<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> were much ſurpriz'd at th<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> thoughts of their Rank, and di<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> not ſuſpect ſo much Gentility a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mong ſuch a People; when w<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> ſaw ſo many <hi>Coats</hi> without <hi>Arms<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
               </hi> we could not imagine they had any with <hi>them,</hi> but fancy'd they had more need of a <hi>Taylor</hi> than o<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>Clarentius,</hi> and of a <hi>Prick-louſe</hi> to ſtitch up and compoſe their <hi>Brea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ches,</hi> rather than an <hi>Herald</hi> to bl<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>zen their <hi>Families.</hi> They appear'd to us to be very ill accoutred Gen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>try: But however vileneſs of <hi>E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quipage</hi> is no blot in <hi>Scutcheon;</hi> a<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> may be eaſily made out from thi<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> following Narrative. When King
<pb n="85" facs="tcp:179526:54"/>
               <hi>James</hi> commanded all that were <hi>Gentlemen</hi> in an Army to paſs by him, he obſerving a <hi>Rag-a muffin</hi> to hobble in the Rear of the Train, commanded him to be ſtopt, becauſe he look'd not like a Gentleman; but <hi>Taphy</hi> cry'd out that hur was as good a Shen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tleman as the beſt, only hur Cat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tle was not ſo good. In their <hi>Travels</hi> they care not much that their Horſes ſhould drink with a <hi>Toſt;</hi> as appears by the wrath which <hi>Shenkin</hi> diſcover'd, whom his quaffing Beaſt had <hi>pitch-pol'd</hi> into a River. <hi>
                  <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>ds-plutter-a-naits</hi> (quoth he) in great fury, what cannot hur drink without a <hi>Toſt?</hi> He took it much in dudgeon, that that the Jade ſhould be ſo <hi>bold</hi> as to make a <hi>Sop</hi> of his Maſter.</p>
            <p>They do not always obſerve the Rules of <hi>Juſtice</hi> in their Puniſh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments; oftentimes chaſtizing one
<pb n="86" facs="tcp:179526:55"/>Body for another, and ſo <hi>miſpl<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> their rigour on the undeſerving as will be very evident from th<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> following Inſtance. A certai<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>Taylor</hi> ferrying over a River <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> their Countrey with a <hi>Diminuti<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> Nag; the Steed never uſing <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> travel by Water, and wonderi<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> that he <hi>ſtood</hi> ſtill and <hi>mov'd,</hi> w<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> poſſeſt with fear, and made ſon <hi>disturbance</hi> in the Boat, to th<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> great endangering of the Paſſe<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gers: The Welch-man being i<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> jeopardy, was <hi>fir'd</hi> with ange<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> and without any wings he <hi>flew</hi> 
               <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> the Taylor, and reveng'd the i<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jury of the <hi>Palfry</hi> on poor Pri<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>louſe. The <hi>Stitcher</hi> ſwadled th<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>ſcrupling</hi> Horſe, and <hi>Taphy</hi> be<gap reason="illegible" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap> the <hi>Stitcher,</hi> to the great <hi>diverſ<gap reason="illegible" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> and <hi>grief</hi> of the Spectators.</p>
            <p>The <hi>Materials</hi> of his Appar<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> are uſually a well ſhagg'd <hi>Fru<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> ſo that we cannot call it <hi>ſle<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi>
               <pb n="87" facs="tcp:179526:55"/>being fleec'd with a <hi>Nap</hi> like any Sheep skin: It affords excellent <hi>barbour</hi> to the Vermin of his Bo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dy, which whether it be ſtockt with ſtore of <hi>Joicements</hi> of them, he commonly ſignifies by the <hi>Sym<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bol</hi> of a ſhrug.</p>
            <p>His <hi>Faſhion</hi> is generally a Pair of <hi>
                  <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>blong</hi> Trowzes made of a Brace of Cloak-bags, ſuppos'd to be Twins; theſe tackt together are a perfect <hi>Emblem</hi> of his <hi>crural</hi> At<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ire. This Garment had <hi>conjugal</hi> Affinity to a thing call'd a Doub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>let of the ſame Linage; a copious Veſtment, very roomthy and ca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pacious, able to comprehend both his Arms in the ſingle Pudding<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bag of one Sleeve; its uppermoſt <hi>confines</hi> were hem'd with the ſcan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty <hi>dimenſions</hi> of a contracted Col<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lar, but its lower <hi>extremity</hi> was border'd with the <hi>Paraphraſe</hi> of <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>mplify'd Lappets. The <hi>Summity</hi>
               <pb n="88" facs="tcp:179526:56"/>of his Head is commonly <hi>crown'<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> with a <hi>Monmouth</hi> Cap, and i<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>Crown</hi> is commonly <hi>pinnacled</hi> wit<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> the <hi>Battlement</hi> of a Button. Cuff<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> are an <hi>Innovation,</hi> things which their Anceſtors were ſeldom guilty of; and indeed <hi>Bands</hi> and clear Linnen are an <hi>upſtart</hi> Invention<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> being the modern effects of the pride of their huge ones, wherea<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>Primitive Brittiſhneſs</hi> was never ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quainted with the <hi>habiliment</hi> of <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>Shirt.</hi> Their Feet it ſeems are o<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> an hot Complexion, for they of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ten air their <hi>diſtockin'd</hi> Pettitoes and if they had any Hoſen they were the <hi>offspring</hi> of their Draw<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ers, to which they were faſten'<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> by Leathern <hi>Ligaments.</hi> The <hi>Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>f<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ction</hi> of a Welch-mans Equipag<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> the <hi>cream</hi> (as it were) of his Ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>coutrements, and that which com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pleats even his moſt <hi>Feſtival</hi> At<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tire, is (as the Story goes) <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap>
               <pb n="89" facs="tcp:179526:56"/>old Sword of hur nown breeding, which hur hath brought up from a Tagger: And this he can brandiſh with much valour againſt the Tre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mendous on-ſet of <hi>Dragooning</hi> Bees; a kind of Enemy which the Taphy is much afraid of, in regard he is always arm'd with a Pike in's Rere, which once upon a time being faſten'd in his Fore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>head, <hi>broacht</hi> ſuch a Pore in his <hi>Phyſiognomy,</hi> that he could never endure thoſe <hi>hum-bazzing</hi> Shen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tlemen (as he calls them) in Yel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>low Doublets.</p>
            <p>The Countrey is mountainous, and yields pretty handſome <hi>clam<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bering</hi> for Goats, and hath variety of Precipice to <hi>break</hi> ones neck; which a Man may ſooner do than <hi>fill</hi> his belly, the Soil being bar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ren, and an excellent place to breed a Famine in. It is reported of <hi>Campania,</hi> That it was the
<pb n="90" facs="tcp:179526:57"/>moſt noble Region in the World, the Air <hi>pleaſant,</hi> the Soil <hi>fertil<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
               </hi> the <hi>Theater</hi> of <hi>Bacchus</hi> and <hi>Ceres,</hi> where they were at <hi>Fiſty-cuffs</hi> for the Preheminence; but we per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceiv'd no ſuch <hi>ſcuffle</hi> in <hi>Wales;</hi> for thoſe Deities are ſo far from <hi>fight<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing</hi> there, that we could not diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cern that they were ſo much as <hi>ever</hi> there; there being ſcarce wa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter and Oat-meal to give us <hi>being,</hi> we could not expect <hi>Aegypt</hi> and the <hi>Canaries,</hi> Butts and Granaries to give us a <hi>well-being:</hi> There is no <hi>Canaan</hi> to be found in the Arms of a <hi>Deſart.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>The <hi>Commodities</hi> of the Nation are chiefly Woollen-cloaths, as Cottons, Bays, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> of which their tatter'd Backs are an ill ſign of; for ſure they are not ſo ſilly to furniſh <hi>other</hi> Countries with Ray<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, and to go naked <hi>them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelves.</hi>
            </p>
            <pb n="91" facs="tcp:179526:57"/>
            <p>As for the <hi>Diet</hi> of the <hi>Britton,</hi> it is not very delicate, neither is he curious in it; for if he ſhould, his <hi>Appetite</hi> perhaps might curſe his <hi>ni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cety,</hi> and by pleaſing his <hi>Palate</hi> he may ſtarve his <hi>Belly.</hi> A good meſs of <hi>Flummery,</hi> a pair of Eggs he re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>joyces at as a Feaſt, eſpecially if he may cloſe his Stomack with <hi>tosted</hi> Cheeſe; a morſel for which he hath a great kindneſs. You may ſee him pictur'd ſometimes with that <hi>crevis</hi> in his Head call'd a Mouth, charg'd at both corners with a <hi>creſcent</hi> of Cheeſe, and himſelf a <hi>cock-horſe</hi> on a Red-herring, and his Hat adorn'd with a <hi>Plume</hi> of Leeks: Good edi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble <hi>Equipage!</hi> which when hunger pinches, he makes bold to nibble; he firſt eats his Cheaſe and his Leeks together, and for ſecond courſe he devours his Horſe. He never much car'd for a <hi>Sop,</hi> ſince once upon a time it <hi>drank</hi> up all
<pb n="92" facs="tcp:179526:58"/>his Drink, and would not <hi>club</hi> to pay his Shot.</p>
            <p>As for his <hi>Perſon,</hi> his ſtature is of the loweſt ſize, not above a Stair or two above one <hi>Story;</hi> and we found always a Cock-loft, and that uſual<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly <hi>empty.</hi> His Face uſually <hi>bubbles</hi> into Tumors and Puſtles. Beſides the natural <hi>Haut-gouſt</hi> of Body that breaths from grain, he uſually ſends forth an <hi>artificial ſmell,</hi> which you may wind as far as the Extream <hi>
                  <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>n<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ction</hi> of twenty Funerals, only the <hi>ſcent</hi> is not ſo ſweet: he ſmells a<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> rankly of the <hi>ſingle</hi> ſtink of Brim<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtone, as a Gold finder of a <hi>medly;</hi> for a ſcurvy Diſeaſe commonly call'd the <hi>Scrubado</hi> makes frequent<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly an <hi>Inroad</hi> into his Perſon, and in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vades his Body; ſo that he is forc'd to choak his Enemy by ſtink of Sulphur. 'Tis a <hi>creeping</hi> Diſtemper, whoſe progreſs is checkt by morti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fication, ſo that when he <hi>leaves of</hi>
               <pb n="93" facs="tcp:179526:58"/>his Shirt, that is, when it <hi>leaves</hi> him, and can hang on no longer, it is excellent Furniture for Tinder<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>box, as <hi>virtually</hi> containing in it. both Match and Tinder.</p>
            <p>The <hi>Muſtck</hi> he plays upon, is a Tool ſtil'd an <hi>Harp,</hi> that is, a <hi>Tri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>angular</hi> ſtick <hi>bed-corded</hi> with varie<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty of extended Catlings; which he <hi>tickles</hi> with as much dexterity, as if prentice to <hi>Amphion,</hi> and draws as many <hi>Boys</hi> after him, as he did <hi>Stones;</hi> nay <hi>theſe</hi> we have ſeen in ſome pla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces to trot after him; but not ſo much to <hi>admire,</hi> as to <hi>pelt</hi> him for his Har<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mony. He puts his Inſtrument to one uſe more than the Ancients did theirs, <hi>i. e.</hi> he <hi>purveys</hi> with it for maintenance; ſo that when ſuſte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nance fails him, he <hi>ſtrikes</hi> up for a Morſel, and ſo lives by <hi>ſounds,</hi> and (Camaeleon like) hath <hi>Alimony</hi> from <hi>Air.</hi> He <hi>ſerenades Victuals</hi> in every Village, as the <hi>Pide-piper</hi> did <hi>Rats</hi>
               <pb n="94" facs="tcp:179526:59"/>at <hi>Hamel,</hi> and he allures <hi>Luncheons</hi> after him, as much as the other did <hi>Vermin:</hi> Here a <hi>knob</hi> of Bacon wag<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> after him, for <hi>one</hi> ſtrain, and there a <hi>Cruſt</hi> follows him as the Reward of <hi>another,</hi> one <hi>hits</hi> him in the Mouth with a payment of <hi>Pottage,</hi> another <hi>pops</hi> him in the Pocket with the <hi>gratuity</hi> of a <hi>Carrot;</hi> he is laden ſome<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>time with ſuch plenty of <hi>Beverege<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
               </hi> that he can't jog for his Fraught; all which variety of <hi>Fragment,</hi> is the moſt ample <hi>In-come,</hi> and wonderful <hi>Revenue</hi> of his skill in Muſick. His uſual Admirers are Countrey Milk maids, whom vibration of ſtring doth move and ſtir into Jig and Meaſure; and whom <hi>Breez</hi> of <hi>Inſtru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment</hi> (like thoſe in <hi>Tayle</hi>) do chafe and tickle into Dance and Caper: By the <hi>wagging</hi> of his Noddle, and the <hi>wrigling</hi> of his Limbs, he ſeem to be taken with the <hi>Accents,</hi> or elſe to be bitten with the <hi>Tarantula</hi> o<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <pb n="95" facs="tcp:179526:59"/>his own M<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ſick, which hath <hi>infected</hi> him into a Ga<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>liard, and caus'd him to fig about with a Frolick Motion.</p>
            <p>We could not perceive that they were guilty of much <hi>Learning;</hi> of which the <hi>loweſt</hi> Degree is ſeveral <hi>notches</hi> above their moſt exalted capacity. We met with one pretty <hi>proband</hi> in the Alphabet; but for the moſt part the knowledge of the leaſt <hi>jota</hi> is rare, and unuſual. A Man skill'd in <hi>Orthography</hi> is admir'd as a <hi>Sophy,</hi> and a writer of his Name is term'd a <hi>Rabbi.</hi> The <hi>Top-gallant</hi> of the Pariſh poſſibly may be ſo wiſe in <hi>Hieroglyphick</hi> as to ſcrawl the Character of a <hi>Mystick</hi> Mark; tho ſuch deep Literature is not frequent amongſt them. Some of their An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſtry have <hi>ſmelt rank</hi> of Aſtrolo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gy; one whereof, <hi>Merlin</hi> by name, was very <hi>notable</hi> at the Stars, and moſt <hi>intimate</hi> with the Planets; in ſo much that ſometimes he would
<pb n="96" facs="tcp:179526:60"/>
               <hi>fling</hi> at a Futurity, and venture at <hi>Prognoſtick</hi> concerning the weath<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> 'Tis ſuppos'd he was bred up at t<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> Feet of ſome <hi>She-Gamaliel,</hi> being <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> well vers'd in the Prophecies of <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> womens <hi>Corns,</hi> and who could <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> cleverly fore-tel Rain, as the lear<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed <hi>Almanack</hi> of the moſt weather wiſe <hi>Toe.</hi> — The ſtudy of <hi>Wizza<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>diſm</hi> hath alſo been famous among<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> them; one Goodman <hi>Druis</hi> was wel<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> accompliſh'd in that kind of Learn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing; hence formerly a <hi>Wizard</hi> wa<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> ſtil'd a <hi>Drue.</hi> This Fellow (they t<gap reason="illegible" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap> us) was the <hi>School-maſter</hi> of <hi>Pyth<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>goras,</hi> into whoſe <hi>Breech</hi> ('tis ſaid) he infus'd by Birch the Opinion <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>Tranſmigration.</hi> He was <hi>dextrous</hi> 
               <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> a Fortune, and <hi>Old-Dog</hi> at Augury the only thing we diſlike in him, i<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> he ſacrific'd Men, and ſo divin<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> by <hi>Butchery.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>To the <hi>Wiſdom</hi> and <hi>Philoſophy</hi> 
               <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> this Sophy, his little Boy <hi>Bard<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi>
               <pb n="97" facs="tcp:179526:60"/>added <hi>Poetry;</hi> a Lad (it ſeems) no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tably inſpir'd with <hi>Flames</hi> and Fire<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>brands, with Heats and Raptures, and ſuch kind of <hi>Tackle</hi> that are us'd by Poets. The Diſciples of this <hi>Laureat</hi> were term'd <hi>Bards,</hi> the great <hi>Embalmers</hi> of Heroick Acti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons; who (I warrant you) will wrap up an Atchievement ſo ſecurely in a <hi>Monument</hi> of a ſingle Verſe, that all the niblings in the world ſhall never be able to devour the <hi>Im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mortality</hi> of a Name. They <hi>ballad-ſung</hi> the Praiſes of Renowned He<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>roes, and in lofty ſtrains <hi>wire-draw'd</hi> their Fame, and <hi>ftretcht</hi> their Glory to after-ages. They were in huge <hi>eſteem,</hi> and had the <hi>Cap</hi> and <hi>Knee</hi> of the greateſt Commanders, in ſo much that if two Armies were even at <hi>Cuffs</hi> or at <hi>Cudgels,</hi> and a venerable <hi>Bard</hi> had ſtept in but with one <hi>Foot</hi> of his Poetry, they would have held their <hi>hands,</hi> and have thrown down their <hi>Hilts,</hi> and have heark<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ned
<pb n="98" facs="tcp:179526:61"/>to the advice of his learne<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>Dactails,</hi> and not offer to ſnout it ti<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> his <hi>Poetical</hi> worſhip had been out <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> danger. The moſt Famous of theſe <hi>Meter-mongers</hi> were <hi>Robbin Pleni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dius,</hi> my Gaffer <hi>Glaskirion,</hi> and of late years old Farmer <hi>Davy,</hi> and ou<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> Neighbour <hi>David ap Williams.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>The <hi>Champions</hi> of the Countrey<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> Men of celebrated Proweſs, were Mr. <hi>Caſſibellane</hi> and Sir <hi>Nennius</hi> Knight, the former whereof was ſo <hi>Doubty</hi> a Blade, that 'tis ſaid he con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fronted <hi>Caeſar,</hi> and bid him kiſs his Back-ſide with undaunted <hi>Gallan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>try;</hi> the other grapling with the ſame Emperor, did <hi>diſwhiniard</hi> his hand by main ſtrength, and ſent the Man home laden with ſome ſtripes<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> and with a <hi>naked</hi> Belt. A notable Inſtance of <hi>Welch</hi> Valour! To theſe we may add that <hi>Hector</hi> of <hi>Brittain<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
               </hi> the Renowned <hi>Arviragus,</hi> who was ſo great a <hi>Raw-head</hi> and <hi>Bloody-bone<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> to the Roman Soldiery, that 'ti<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <pb n="99" facs="tcp:179526:61"/>thought he frighted them even to the <hi>bewraying</hi> of their Breeches, and made them mightily <hi>ſtink</hi> of a <hi>fil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thy</hi> diſcomfiture.</p>
            <p>As for the <hi>Loves</hi> of the <hi>Brittons,</hi> the Intrigues of their <hi>Amours</hi> are not a little remarkable; they being very pretty <hi>Animals</hi> when <hi>diſguis'd</hi> with that Paſſion: They are <hi>Tinder</hi> to ſuch Flames, being quickly ſet on fire, even by the leaſt ſpark, which when it hath catch'd the <hi>Match</hi> of their Souls, (for they have <hi>Brimſtone</hi> in them as well as in their Bodies) they are preſently kindled into <hi>Tranſport</hi> and <hi>Extaſie;</hi> and theſe model them into the ſhapes of a thouſand <hi>Anticks,</hi> and make them ſhew more tricks than <hi>Banks</hi> his Horſe. Sometimes they are ſhaking the <hi>Globules</hi> of their Noddle, and ſometimes dancing ſome <hi>Geometry</hi> with the <hi>Figures</hi> of their <hi>Feet;</hi> now they ſmite with <hi>clapper</hi> of Fiſt their troubled Breaſts, and anon ſound
<pb n="100" facs="tcp:179526:62"/>out ſome Knells of diſmal Groan<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> being variouſly affected accordin<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> as the <hi>weather</hi> is in their <hi>Clorinda<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> Faces; if <hi>Aſpect</hi> be clear, then i<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> Taphy <hi>Serene;</hi> if <hi>Brow</hi> be cloudy then is <hi>Morgan Showry.</hi> He com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>monly <hi>ore-flows</hi> in his prattle about the <hi>Princum prancumneſs</hi> of his Mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtreſs, and is witty even to a Jeſt on the Fineries of their Habiliments, in deſcribing of which he is pretty lucky at <hi>Similitude,</hi> and is happy in his <hi>Compariſons</hi> about her Perſon. One having a glympſe through the Key-hole of her <hi>Saffron</hi> Body, burſt out into a Panegyrick of the <hi>Bees-waxneſs</hi> (as he phras'd it) of her <hi>Tawny</hi> Complexion; and ſeeing her <hi>Tippet</hi> to briſtle into the erectneſs of a <hi>Turbant,</hi> he fell a laughing at the <hi>Cox-comb</hi> (as he term'd it) of her Coif and Head-gear. He ſeldom troubles his Madam with the ſalu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tation of a Letter, but uſually accoſts her with the <hi>Miſſive</hi> (as I may ſay)
<pb n="101" facs="tcp:179526:62"/>of his nown Perſon, which being broken up in her preſence, <hi>out fly</hi> the Contents full of flame and rapture.</p>
            <lg>
               <l>
                  <hi>Shentle Modeſt! when hur ſee</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>The Fair Looks her made at me,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Hur could not chooſe by what's above,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>But be entangled by her Love.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Hur was not think it fit and meet,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>To wrap hur Love within a</hi> Sheet;</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>But was think it great deal better,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>To ſpeak hur Loufe than write a Letter;</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Hoping her not exception take</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>At hur for hur Countreys ſake.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>What if hur Welch-man be? what then?</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Taffies <hi>was all</hi> Shentlemen;</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Born from</hi> Venus <hi>that fair</hi> Coddeſs,</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>And many other</hi> Shentle Bodies;</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Part Humane and part Difine,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>We are d<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ſcended from</hi> Joves <hi>Line.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>All this Truth her dare not mince,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Being the</hi> Iſſue <hi>of</hi> Brittiſh <hi>Prince.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>If ſhould with</hi> Shenkin <hi>drink ſome Wine,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Her would think her Fortune</hi> fine,</l>
               <pb n="102" facs="tcp:179526:63"/>
               <l>
                  <hi>And hur would tell ſuch Tale in Ear</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>That all the Wor<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>d was never hear.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Then Shentle Modeſt let hur prove,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Honeſt</hi> Shenkin <hi>will hur love;</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Though hur was very filthy fit,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>That drives poor Welchman out of wit</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>And if hur will not pity hur pain,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Hur will never Loufe again.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <p>We heard of one that went a wooing with a <hi>Gun</hi> upon his ſhoul<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der, being reſolv'd (it ſeems) if Love be a <hi>warfare,</hi> not to enter unarm'd into the <hi>Camp</hi> of <hi>Venus;</hi> ſtill as his coy <hi>Daphne</hi> ſhifted from his pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſence, he marcht <hi>Musketeering</hi> about the Room, and moſt fiercely purſu'd her, till at laſt in the brisk Encoun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter of a cloſe Embrace, this warlike Inſtrument took an occaſion ſome<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>what unmannerly to go off, and <hi>Blunderbuſs'd</hi> the Miſtreſs on her <hi>Breech</hi> on one ſide of the houſe, and poor Taphy on his <hi>Noſe</hi> on the o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther; ſo that being much diſmay'd at this unhappy Accident, one
<pb n="103" facs="tcp:179526:63"/>ſcrabled one way, and the other a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nother, to the total ſeparation of a pair of Lovers, and to the utter ſpilling of a <hi>Meſs</hi> of Love.</p>
            <p>They are pretty devout in their worſhip, though the exerciſe of <hi>Religion</hi> is ſomewhat ſcarce, and have a pretty <hi>glowing</hi> zeal, though their Churches are <hi>few,</hi> and at a great <hi>diſtance.</hi> 'Tis almoſt incredible how far they are fain to trudge for a little <hi>Homily,</hi> which when they have expected, have been <hi>mump'd</hi> with a <hi>Sermon</hi> ten times worſe. For on ſuch <hi>Raw-bone</hi> Livings there can<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>not be expected very <hi>plump</hi> Parts. The ordinary Revenue of a Spiri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tual Preferment may poſſibly be a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bout <hi>five Marks per Annum;</hi> a Bay of Watling for a dwelling, endow'd with no more Glebe than juſt what it ſtands upon, only perhaps it may be <hi>howe-ſtall'd</hi> with as much ground as may hold a <hi>Sty</hi> for the Pig, and a <hi>Rooſt</hi> for the Pullen. Theſe Divine
<pb n="104" facs="tcp:179526:64"/>Cottages are uſually ſituated ſom<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> Leagues from the Temple; ſo tha<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> the Holy-man with Crab-tree Tru<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>cheon ſets out with the Sun, an<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> ſtretcheth his <hi>Legs</hi> with a goo<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> handſome walk, before he arrives to <hi>Pulpit</hi> to ſtretch his <hi>Lungs,</hi> and wea<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> out much of his <hi>Soles</hi> before he can reach his <hi>Stall</hi> to mend their <hi>Souls.</hi> Their Houſes of Prayer are gene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rally <hi>Thatcht Tabernacles,</hi> which be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing ſteepled (as it were) with a <hi>Lo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver-hole,</hi> ſeem to be really that what the <hi>Temple</hi> reſembled when pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>phan'd by the <hi>Jews,</hi> I mean, rather the Pictures of <hi>Pidgeon-houſes,</hi> than holy <hi>Sanctuaries.</hi> They are wain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcoted towards the Eaſt with little Desks, like Pounds, where Levite impriſon'd for about half an hour, <hi>fodders</hi> the poor Taffies with ſome melancholly <hi>Tear-fetching</hi> Story a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bout a Grim Fellow call'd <hi>Death,</hi> who <hi>ambles</hi> Folks on his back into another World; a thing which he
<pb n="105" facs="tcp:179526:64"/>heard from the <hi>Oracular</hi> Gums of of his <hi>edentulous</hi> old Grannum, as ſhe ſate in the Settle in the Chimney<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>corner. Some of the moſt <hi>Reverend</hi> Rectors are dignify'd with a ſtipend of <hi>ſix pounds</hi> a year, beſides the <hi>Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quiſites</hi> of a Drum and Fiddle; which well manag'd on a Holy-day, make up a very pretty Thing. Others have an <hi>Augmentation</hi> of a Bull or a Bear, which being ſolemnly baited about twice in a Quarter, do pick pretty comfortable <hi>Tyth</hi> from the Specta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tors Pockets, and makes the poor Parſons Purſe to ſmile and <hi>mantle.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Their <hi>Recreations</hi> are various, but not much different from thoſe in <hi>England;</hi> you may ſee them ſome<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>times ſmite a <hi>Ball</hi> at the Rebound, and to ſend it on an errand to their Antagoniſts, which being retorted by way of Anſwer, is <hi>rejoinder'd</hi> back again with much dexterity. They will bandy to and fro this <hi>miſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſile Globule,</hi> and <hi>ſhittle-cock</hi> it to each
<pb n="106" facs="tcp:179526:65"/>other with great celerity. Their Lungs are pretty good at a Bubble in the Air, which <hi>Meteor</hi> ariſing from the Womb of a Wallnut-ſhell, they will make <hi>fly</hi> through the <hi>Welkin</hi> on the <hi>Wings</hi> of their Breaths, and for a conſiderable time, by the Blaſts of their Mouths, will ſupport the Be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing of thoſe <hi>Emblems</hi> of Mortality.</p>
            <p>In the <hi>whity-brown</hi> Evening, or in the Twilight, they run hobling a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bout their Common with <hi>Kites</hi> at their heels, certain Comets of Paper, which they tow along with a tall ſtring, and make themſelves merry with the length of their Tails, which are a large <hi>Series</hi> of jaggd Toſſels, rag'd with a Candle, as with the twinkling of a Star. Happy is the Man amongſt them that can moſt diſcreetly manage this Artificial Planet; and he is preſently <hi>dub'd</hi> the very <hi>Phaeton</hi> of their Countrey, that can moſt ſwiftly career it with this little <hi>lanthern'd</hi> Phoebus. The
<pb n="107" facs="tcp:179526:65"/>
               <hi>Scrubs</hi> want Candle on <hi>Earth,</hi> and yet they muſt needs be ſticking up <hi>Lights</hi> in the Socket of <hi>Heaven;</hi> there's ſcarce half a pound in a Lordſhip either to ſcare away dark<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs or to <hi>work by,</hi> and yet theſe Raſcals (forſooth) will be <hi>ſtudding</hi> the Skie with Luminaries to <hi>play by.</hi> — As for true and real <hi>Hunting,</hi> there is no ſuch thing among them; only they have (as it were) the <hi>Pi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cture</hi> and ſome kind of <hi>reſemblance</hi> of that Paſtime; for their Principa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lity affording them but few Hares, they courſe a <hi>Lock of Hay</hi> in lieu thereof, and Alloo the <hi>Puſs</hi> of a good nimble wiſp. The <hi>whim</hi> of it is this; when they have a mind to refreſh themſelves with ſomewhat that is a kin to, or with an <hi>Idea</hi> of Hunting, they make diligent ſearch for a Furlong or two of ſmooth and champion ground, which at laſt be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing found, they purchaſe a Bundle of the ſwifteſt Hay, (if <hi>Iriſh,</hi> 'tis the
<pb n="108" facs="tcp:179526:66"/>better, for there are the beſt Run<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners of all ſorts) this they expoſe to the Fans of <hi>Aeolus,</hi> which being preſently ſtarted by force of puff, it ſcuds away, and the Dogs purſue it with mighty ſpeed. In rainy wea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther they have alſo their <hi>In-door</hi> Divertiſements as well as other Nations, ſuch as <hi>Rump-preſſing, Hot<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cockles, Chap-ſmutting, Snap-apple,</hi> and the like. Some are cunning at the <hi>Cockall,</hi> not ſo much for <hi>picking</hi> off the meat (though they are good at that too) as at <hi>throwing</hi> it with accuracy, and <hi>checquering</hi> the ſport with <hi>variety</hi> of Tumble.</p>
            <p>As far as we could perceive, they love <hi>Holy-day</hi> Fingers, and care not much for encumbring them with that <hi>Inconvenience</hi> call'd <hi>work.</hi> They can (Shepherd like) loll upon a crook pretty handſomely in the Field, and can diſcharge a <hi>ſuperin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tendency</hi> over the Goats. They are moſt accompliſh'd <hi>Drov<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>rs,</hi> to
<pb n="109" facs="tcp:179526:66"/>which laudable Function they are ſo naturally prone, that they are apt to <hi>arive</hi> ſometimes <hi>more</hi> than their own.</p>
            <p>They are much addicted to the ſin of <hi>Naſtineſs,</hi> wallowing in filthi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs like ſo many Swine; ſo that the whole Province ſeems to be but a general <hi>Sty.</hi> You may ſwear they are made of <hi>Earth</hi> without a Me<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>taphor; appearing like ſo many <hi>Dirt-Images,</hi> or like that of <hi>Prome<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>theus</hi> made of <hi>clay.</hi> The meaner ſort of Women are generally ſuch <hi>Drag<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gle-Tails,</hi> that the Cattle in their Boſoms are <hi>quag-mir'd</hi> in the filth of their <hi>well-gleb'd</hi> Attire; ſo that the frisking Fleas are ſo far from <hi>Levalto's,</hi> that we are verily per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſwaded they can ſcarce pull out <hi>Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>boſcis,</hi> and their Feet from the Bogs.</p>
            <p>The <hi>Tenements</hi> they live in are ſutable to the <hi>Gueſts</hi> that poſſeſs them; for as theſe ſeem to be <hi>Dirt</hi> moulded into <hi>Men,</hi> ſo thoſe are the
<pb n="110" facs="tcp:179526:67"/>ſame matter kneaded into <hi>Houſes</hi> 
               <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> they are uſually very <hi>Humble</hi> Cotta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ges, and low in ſtature, ſo that a Ma<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> may ride upon the Ridge, and yet have his Legs hang in the Dirt; thoſe that are ſo magnificent as to be <hi>cre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſted</hi> with a Chimney, are mightily valu'd, as moſt <hi>Cocking</hi> Fabricks. We were not ſo vain as to expect very ſplendid Furniture in ſuch contemptible <hi>Hutts;</hi> but we ſoon perceiv'd what Utenſils were moſt neceſſary; a Diſh-clout and a Bee<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> ſome, and ſuch cleanſing <hi>Implement<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> are very proper to correct the fil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thineſs of their Manſions; we found no <hi>Apartments</hi> in theſe their Habi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tations, every Edifice being a <hi>Noah<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> Ark,</hi> where a <hi>Promiſcuous</hi> Family a <hi>Miſcellaneous</hi> Heap of all kind o<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> Creatures did converſe together in one Room; the Pigs and the Pulle<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> and other Brutes either truckling under, or lying at the Beds-feet o<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> the little more <hi>refin'd,</hi> yet thei<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <pb n="111" facs="tcp:179526:67"/>
               <hi>Brother</hi> Animals. The Countrey is fortifi'd in ſome places with a pretty <hi>ſprinkling</hi> of Caſtles, which whether they naturally <hi>grew</hi> out of the Rocks, or were artificially <hi>ingrafted</hi> there, may be a matter of diſpute; ſome fancy'd them to be <hi>Stone-pits ſhot</hi> up into th' Air, which repre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent the Figure of vaſt Buildings.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Wales</hi> is the moſt monſtrous <hi>Limb</hi> in the whole <hi>Body</hi> of Geography, for 'tis generally reported to be without a <hi>middle,</hi> or if it hath a <hi>Navel</hi> 'tis yet a <hi>Terra Incognita;</hi> for we never could find that ever any Man dwelt there, the Natives con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feſſing themſelves to be only <hi>Bor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>derers.</hi> Surely the reaſon why they do ſo much affect the <hi>circumference</hi> of their Countrey, and abominate the <hi>center,</hi> is, becauſe they are a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſham'd of the Dominion; and in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deed 'tis a ſign they have but a lit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>le kindneſs for their Nation, who <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> like unnatural Sons) run from
<pb n="112" facs="tcp:179526:68"/>their Mother their Country, a<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> when out of her Embraces nev<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> return again. A Welch-man wh<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> once abroad, hath no more tende<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cy <hi>home,</hi> than a Stone an Inclinat<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on to fall upward: He will trot o'<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> the Globe, &amp; rather endure the i<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fliction of any Exile, than the crue<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>puniſhment of being <hi>baniſht</hi> hom<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> if he is once on this ſide <hi>Dee,</hi> nei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther <hi>Hunger</hi> nor <hi>Husks,</hi> nor any kin<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> of hardſhip ſhall drive him on the other.</p>
            <p>We could not in our Travel wind very many <hi>Feaſts</hi> amon<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> them, the ſhabbyneſs of their Soi<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> being not able to nouriſh and po<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>per Luxury, ſo that a Cook, unle<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> he exerciſe on himſelf, and dre<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> his own Fingers, he is immediatel<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> ſtarv'd here for want of an E<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ployment. They make ſome litt<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> Invitations perhaps to a <hi>Kids-hea<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> or ſo; and will junket with <hi>Hop<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tops</hi> with brisk alacrity. Such plai<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <pb n="113" facs="tcp:179526:68"/>mean (and as I may ſay) <hi>Burrough</hi> Food was even their <hi>Festival</hi> En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tertainments; but as for any <hi>Em<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>broider'd</hi> and (as it were) <hi>Metro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>politan</hi> Meſs, ſuch as Bisks and Og<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>io's, we never ſo much as heard of them in their Territories.</p>
            <p>Their Mart for Law is a Pariſh Town call'd <hi>Ludlow,</hi> where there <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>s a Court of Judicature <hi>deckt</hi> with <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> Judge, Counſellors, Attorneys, Sollicitors, and other <hi>Furniture</hi> which <hi>embelliſh</hi> the Law: Hither <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>hey trudge for Deciſion of Caſe, <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>nd here <hi>Red-coat Integrity</hi> diſpen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>es <hi>Equity.</hi> Moſt of their Indict<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ents are generally the Tragical effects of ſome diſmal <hi>Counter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>cuffle;</hi> where a bloody <hi>Noſe</hi> and <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> broken <hi>Shin</hi> is ample matter for <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>he Commencement of a <hi>Suit;</hi> for <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>hey being of a fiery temper, ſome<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>imes chol<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>r is kindled by an <hi>Anti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>periſtaſis</hi> with a Pot of Ale; and then
<pb n="114" facs="tcp:179526:69"/>they fall to biting and ſcratchin<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> as hard as they can drive, and t<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> wounds of this <hi>Caterwauling</hi> an<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> Bickering affords ſtuff for an Act on the next day; which being onc<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> got into the <hi>Pounces</hi> of a Welch A<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>torney, is <hi>dandled</hi> into a Buſineſs <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> no ſmall aggravation. Oh! Ho<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> theſe Pettifoggers will <hi>hug</hi> a Buffe<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, and improve a Squobble? They are the very <hi>Bellows</hi> of Contentio<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> and will ſoon blow a <hi>Spark</hi> into <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> great <hi>Combuſtion.</hi> They are a kin<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> of <hi>Tinkers</hi> in the Law, who uſuall<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>make</hi> holes on purpoſe that the<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> may <hi>mend</hi> them; nay ſometimes the<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> will play at <hi>Loggerhead</hi> themſelves to ſet others together by the <hi>Ear<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> and ſo (as if fighting was conta<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ous) will <hi>infect</hi> the Taphies int<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> Quarrels and Blows. One marchin<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> along the Streets advanc'd th<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>Scolding</hi> of two Women into <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> huge <hi>Tumult,</hi> as Duels ſwell into
<pb n="115" facs="tcp:179526:69"/>great Wars; and made the <hi>ſnarl<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing</hi> of two Dogs <hi>thrive</hi> into an A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ction, and the fighting of Maſtiffs to end in the Court of the <hi>Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon-Pleas.</hi> They commonly broach Quarrels, and incenſe the Shen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tlemen into knockings and ſmi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tings, crack'd Crowns, and black Eyes, into Aſſaults and Batteries, and all for hopes of a Livelihood that may be <hi>skim</hi>'d from the bene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fit of ſuch Wars: But perhaps the <hi>Spoils</hi> from the Skirmiſhes of ſuch <hi>Clients</hi> are as rare as <hi>Pillage</hi> from a <hi>Scotch</hi> Army. The uſual crime for which they ſtand generally convi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cted, is that great tranſgreſſion and <hi>ſin</hi> of <hi>Mice,</hi> the nimming of Cheeſe, and the filching of Oat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>meal, and of the reſt of the good Creatures that are <hi>Arkt</hi> in the Cup-board; and as they <hi>offend like</hi> Vermin, ſo are ordinarily <hi>ta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ken</hi> ſo too, that is, not <hi>apprehen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ded</hi>
               <pb n="116" facs="tcp:179526:70"/>like Men, but <hi>entrap</hi>'d like Rats; after which they are co<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vented before the Sage <hi>Puſs</hi> of th<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> Law, which purring upon a T<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bunal together with his <hi>Kitli<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>g</hi> Officers, doth faſten on the Prey and doth ſo ſuck and claw it, t<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> it hath mumbled out all its <hi>Blood</hi> that is, all the <hi>Money</hi> of its Vein<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> and then wholly devours it. Th<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> (I ſay) is <hi>one</hi> of their offence<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> though not the <hi>only</hi> one; for ſom<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> of them have been laſht for a<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> attempt upon <hi>Hen-Rooſts,</hi> and have receiv'd condign puniſhment eve<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> for ſtealing of Poultry at th<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>wrong end;</hi> for Taphy (it ſeems) having filch'd a Chicken by th<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> Breech, did <hi>diſrump</hi> her by h<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> Theft; and therefore in reſem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>blance to his Crime was almoſt <hi>diſrumpt.</hi> by puniſhment; ſo that for ſtealing the <hi>Birds</hi> Tail, he had well-nigh loſt his <hi>own:</hi> A pretty
<pb n="117" facs="tcp:179526:70"/>Circumſtance obſerv'd in their Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtice! and a laudable way of pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceeding according to <hi>Lex Ta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lionis.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>For ſeveral Crimes they have various Puniſhments. That grand Enormity of <hi>Breaking wind</hi> is cha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtiz'd there as 'tis in <hi>England,</hi> that is the hand of Magiſtracy doth uſually inflict a pretty luſty <hi>Cob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling,</hi> that is, for every Report the loſs of an Hair, though ſome that have been much addicted to that Infirmity, and therefore have been very <hi>guilty</hi> of a ſtink, have in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dur'd the cruelty of tormenting Faries, that is, have been pinch'd into manners, and a better <hi>ſmell.</hi> Artificers when at work puniſh any unhandſome Action by a particu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lar ſeverity peculiar to themſelves, which they call <hi>Purſing.</hi> The Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ecution whereof is after this man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner: The Malefactor being pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtrate
<pb n="118" facs="tcp:179526:71"/>on a Block, two of the ſa<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> occupation pull as <hi>diſcreetly</hi> as they can his Drawers as cloſe to But<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tock as a <hi>Spaniards</hi> Breeches, ſo <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> not to be laid hold on by the m<gap reason="illegible" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap> curious Pinſers; the <hi>Pavement</hi> 
               <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> Poſteriours being level'd a<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> ſmooth'd from any wrinkles, <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> third Artiſan ſtrikes it with a Rul<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> whoſe ſmart Application by <hi>Quick jerks</hi> makes ſome impreſſion of pain, and ſo moves the Blood <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> to raiſe and ſtart a Tincture a<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> (as it were) the <hi>Flea-biting</hi> of Bluſh. Some of the more obſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nate Criminals are puniſh'd <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>ſuſpenſion,</hi> but not by the Neol as here in <hi>England,</hi> but by <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> wriſts, <hi>Thumb-rop'd</hi> together wi<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> a ſtring of Hay, and ſo faſten<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> to a Peg; well! this is but the be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ginning (and as it were) the <hi>Hiſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſing</hi> of the Puniſhment, do <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> mark, and the <hi>Sting</hi> will follow<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
               <pb n="119" facs="tcp:179526:71"/>The offending Taphy thus dang<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling in the Air, the Beadle ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>proaches with a ſtick <hi>impt</hi> with a Feather at one end, and tickles his Teſticles; theſe ſofter Titilla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions engender ſome <hi>vibrations</hi> of Body, and nimble Friskings, which are ſhrewdly chaſtiz'd by a ſurly <hi>Cat-of-nine-tails.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>The Cattle we ſaw moſt <hi>legible</hi> on their Mountains were Goats and Heifers; a runtiſh ſort of A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nimals, of a <hi>dwarfiſh</hi> ſize, but very <hi>hardy,</hi> of a flinty Conſtitu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion <hi>calculated</hi> on purpoſe for the <hi>meridian</hi> of a Rock; on which (it ſeems) they can as heartily feed, as an <hi>Oſtrich</hi> on an Anvil. Great numbers of theſe are often <hi>diſembogu'd</hi> into adjacent Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tries, which after ſome time <hi>cir<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>culate</hi> home again in a <hi>ſtream</hi> of Money; which yields wonderful refreſhment to the fainting Domi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nion,
<pb n="120" facs="tcp:179526:72"/>almoſt ſick for the comfor<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> of ſuch a Cordial. We perceiv<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> their Herds to be frequently ming<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>led with little Palfries; a ſtunted ſort of Horſes, diminutive Brutes <hi>Shavals</hi> in ſhort-hand. They a<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>lower</hi> in ſtature than an Aſſe, <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> much <hi>ſwifter</hi> in Foot, and very ſtrong, as it appears from their Burdens, which are oftentimes the <hi>Fortune</hi> and Subſtance of a whole Family; for when a Mortal breaks he mounts all he hath on <hi>Welch Nag,</hi> and travels under the Cha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>racter of a <hi>Scotch Pedlar.</hi> W<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> chanc'd to ſee a Team of th<gap reason="illegible" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap> ſmall Cattle, a rare Spectacle, <gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing (as we ſuppos'd) the le<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> that ever was heard of, unl<gap reason="illegible" extent="3 letters">
                  <desc>•••</desc>
               </gap> that which was harneſs'd in <hi>Ven<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> her Chariot, which was a Tea<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> of <hi>Doves.</hi> Theſe Brittiſh Steed are ſo brisk and Mercurial, th<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> the People would perſwade <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap>
               <pb n="121" facs="tcp:179526:72"/>that a <hi>Taphy</hi> on a <hi>Tit</hi> would out<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtrip in travel an <hi>Arabian</hi> on a <hi>Dromedary;</hi> a thing almoſt incre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dible, though the <hi>pricking</hi> up their Ears, and the <hi>ſticking</hi> up their Tails, is an Argument of their Metal, and may give ſome colour and ground for the Aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſertion.</p>
            <p>That which we admir'd moſt of all amongſt them, was the <hi>Virgi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nity</hi> of their Language, not de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>flowr'd by the mixture of any o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Dialect: The purity of <hi>La<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tine</hi> was debauch'd by the <hi>Vandals,</hi> and was <hi>Hun'd</hi> into corruption by that barbarous People; but the ſincerity of the Brittiſh remains <hi>inviolable.</hi> 'Tis a Tongue (it ſeems) not made for every Mouth; as appears by an Inſtance of one in our Company, who having got a Welch <hi>Polyſyllable</hi> into his Throat, was almoſt choak'd with <hi>Conſo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nants,</hi>
               <pb n="122" facs="tcp:179526:73"/>had we not by clapping him on the back made him <hi>diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gorge</hi> a Guttural or two, and ſo ſav'd him. They uſually <hi>liqueſ<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> the moſt rugged Mutes, and ſof<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ten 'um by Pronuntiation; melt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing the word Tug into Tudge a<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> is clear from this Diſtick.</p>
            <p>Still he did <hi>Tudge</hi> hur Ear</p>
            <p>In praiſe of the <hi>Tirteen</hi> Seer, <hi>i. e.</hi> did <hi>Tug</hi> hur Souſes with Elo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>giums of hur Countrey. Whether the Welch Tongue be a <hi>Splinter</hi> of that univerſal one that was ſhatter'd at <hi>Babel,</hi> we have ſome reaſon to doubt, in regard 'tis un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>like the Dialects that were <hi>crum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bled</hi> there: However, whether <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> be kin or no to other Countrey Speeches, it matters not; but this we are aſſur'd of, it is <hi>near</hi> and <hi>dear</hi> to the Folk that utter it, who are ſo paſſionately fond of it, that they will ſcarce admit another
<pb n="123" facs="tcp:179526:73"/>into the <hi>Embraces</hi> of their Lips, which ſputter forth a kind of loathing of our <hi>Engliſh</hi> Language; wherein, if a Queſtion be ask'd them, they will with ſomewhat of diſdain and choler make an<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſwer <hi>Dim ſaiſſonick, i. e.</hi> no <hi>Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liſh.</hi> Their Native <hi>Gibberiſh</hi> is u<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſually pratled throughout the whole <hi>Taphydome,</hi> except in their Market-Towns, whoſe Inhabitants being a little rais'd, and (as it were) pufft up into <hi>Bubbles</hi> above the ordinary <hi>Scum,</hi> do begin to deſpiſe it. Some of theſe being elevated above the common Le<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vel, and perhaps refin'd into the Quality of having <hi>two Suits,</hi> are apt to fancy themſelves above their Tongue, and when in their <hi>t'other Cloaths,</hi> are quite aſham'd on't. 'Tis uſually caſhier'd out of Gentlemens Houſes, there being ſcarcely to be heard even one ſingle
<pb n="124" facs="tcp:179526:74"/>Welch Tone in many Families; their Children are inſtructed in the <hi>Anglican</hi> Ideom, and their Schools are <hi>Paedagogu'd</hi> with Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feſſors of the ſame; ſo that (if the Stars prove lucky) there may be ſome <hi>glimmering</hi> hopes that the Brittiſh <hi>Lingua</hi> may be quite ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tinct, and may be <hi>Engliſh'd</hi> out of <hi>Wales,</hi> as <hi>Latin</hi> was barbarouſly <hi>Goth'd</hi> out of <hi>Italy.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>The <hi>Cambro-Brittons</hi> are great admirers of Heroick Actions, and much honour the Memory of Fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mous Atchievements; in ſo much that rather than a <hi>Dead-doing</hi> Ma<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> ſhall periſh in Oblivion, they will <gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>ernize his Name by the Mon<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of a <hi>Straw,</hi> or ſome ſuch <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> conſiderable trifle; as appears by that Famous Example of that Saint of their Countrey, Biſhop <hi>David,</hi> who being a pert fighter and having ſoundly <hi>baſted</hi> and
<pb n="125" facs="tcp:179526:74"/>ſwadled their Foes, is at this day conſecrated to Poſterity by the <hi>Trophy</hi> of a Leek; and <hi>ſmells</hi> as rank of Renown from that Vege<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>table <hi>Preſervative</hi> that Embalms his Fame, as they do of a <hi>Scallion</hi> that carry it about for his Glory. Their Hats are ſet with this Ani<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verſary <hi>Badge</hi> and <hi>Emblem</hi> of Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nour, and triumph on the firſt of <hi>March;</hi> which Day hath been chriſten'd by his Name, and being <hi>Dub'd</hi> an Holy-day, hath worn yearly in the Almanack a <hi>Scarlet</hi> Letter.</p>
            <p>There is <hi>one thing</hi> more alſo ve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry <hi>obſervable</hi> among them, and that is, that of all the main'd Perſons that ever we read of, we find none comparable for nimble<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs to a <hi>Cambrian Cripple;</hi> a preg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nant Proof whereof was preſent<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed to us in this following Inſtance; A Fellow with Crutches mov'd by
<pb n="126" facs="tcp:179526:75"/>
               <hi>Protruſion</hi> in a certain Wheel-bar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>row, eſpying a Bear near the Rere of the <hi>Thruſter,</hi> was ſo ſurpriz'd with horror at this tremendom ſight, that he pack'd up his <hi>Pede<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtals, i. e.</hi> tuck'd his Oaken <hi>Shins</hi> to the <hi>Zodiack</hi> of his Girdle, and away he fled; <hi>Bruin</hi> and the <hi>Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>truſor</hi> in vain troop'd after him, who led them a risk with ſuch winged ſpeed, that they could never o're take him; He clearly out-ſtript them, to the Eternal Glory and Renown of <hi>Welch Lame<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Theſe are ſome of the <hi>choiceſt</hi> Obſervations we made when con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verſant among the <hi>Brittiſh</hi> Moun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tains; we might eaſily have ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ded more, (the whole Nation in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deed being but <hi>one grand Remark</hi>) had not the ſuddenneſs of our Return preyented us. If it ſhould chance to be our Lot to ſet our
<pb n="127" facs="tcp:179526:75"/>Feet on that Soil a ſecond time, we ſhall venture to preſent ano<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther <hi>Show</hi> of it; for 'tis pity ſuch a rare ſight as <hi>Wales</hi> ſhould want a <hi>Trumpet,</hi> nay and a <hi>Fool</hi> too to proclaim and expoſe it to the World.</p>
            <p>After we had cram'd our <hi>Budget</hi> with theſe few Notices, we jog'd on with our Fraught to the Brink of the Sea, where <hi>mounted</hi> on a Pinnace we rode to <hi>Bristol,</hi> from whence with all poſſible ſpeed we trudg'd in a few days to the <hi>Metropolis</hi> of the Nation call'd <hi>London.</hi>
            </p>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
            <pb facs="tcp:179526:76"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:179526:76"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:179526:77"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:179526:77"/>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
